<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<schedule>
  <conference>
    <title>FOSDEM 2007</title>
    <subtitle>Free and Open source Software Developers' European Meeting</subtitle>
    <venue>ULB (Université Libre de Bruxelles)</venue>
    <city>Brussels</city>
    <start>2007-02-25</start>
    <end>2007-02-26</end>
    <days>2</days>
    <day_change>09:00:00</day_change>
    <timeslot_duration>00:05:00</timeslot_duration>
  </conference>
  <day index="1" date="2007-02-25">
  <event id="0">
      <start>15:00</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>Chavanne</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>AIGLX</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Desktop Applications</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, Kristian will take a look at technologies behind the new 3D accelerated composited desktops and see how &lt;a href=&#34;http://fedoraproject.org/wiki/RenderingProject/aiglx&#34;&gt;AIGLX&lt;/a&gt; fits in the larger picture.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://fedoraproject.org/wiki/RenderingProject/aiglx&#34;&gt;AIGLX&lt;/a&gt; is a new feature in the X.org X server, which lets the server use hardware 3D drivers to accelerate indirect GLX rendering.&#xA;This enables Open GL based compositing managers such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://go-compiz.org/&#34;&gt;compiz&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://beryl-project.org/&#34;&gt;beryl&lt;/a&gt; to efficiently use the pixel contents of a window as an Open GL texture.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Finally, Kristian will show us some of the bottlenecks and feature regressions of the AIGLX approach and how new developments in the open source 3D&#xA;stack can help address these problems.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1">Kristian Høgsberg</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://video.fosdem.org/2007/FOSDEM2007-AIGLX.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="5">
      <start>16:00</start>
      <duration>00:30</duration>
      <room>H.2214</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Belgian eID card on CentOS</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>CentOS + Fedora</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Explanations about and How to use the belgian eID card under CentOS Linux&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Belgian government decided some years ago to release newer identity cards for Belgian citizens in an electronic format (eID cards). What can we do with these cards on CentOS Linux ? This little presentation will cover first an introduction about the eID card and possible eID readers available on the market. Which software is needed to recognize the card/reader and how to use it with opensource programs like Firefox and Thunderbird to authenticate (in a web session) or sign (a mail) with the certificates sitting on the card.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="51">Fabian Arrotin</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://wiki.centos.org/Events/Fosdem2007?action=AttachFile&amp;do=get&amp;target=eid-card-centos-fosdem07.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="6">
      <start>14:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>H.2214</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Introduction to CentOS + Q&amp;A</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>CentOS + Fedora</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What is CentOS? Where did it come from? Who is responsible for it? And who needs an enterprise distribution anyhow?&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CentOS is an enterprise class linux distribution with a strong, fast growing active community behind it. This talk will give an overview of the distribution and the people behind it. After a short &amp;#34;historical&amp;#34; overview this talk will center on the available CentOS versions, and give an overview of what is in the distribution. This talk is also trying to explain in which fields an enterprise class distribution might be useful for the user or the administrator. Showing the places where the community is doing work at the moment and a brief introduction of the technical aspects behind CentOS will top off this talk.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="61">Ralph Angenendt</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://wiki.centos.org/Events/Fosdem2007?action=AttachFile&amp;do=get&amp;target=fosdem2007.tar.gz">Slides (PDF)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="8">
      <start>16:30</start>
      <duration>00:30</duration>
      <room>H.2214</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>OpenVZ virtualization on CentOS</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>CentOS + Fedora</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As server consolidation becomes more and more important in the IT workplace, virtualization becomes more and more important. OpenVZ is operating system-level virtualization technology that can deliver this virtualization need on CentOS.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This presentation will layout the major differences between OpenVZ and other better known virtualization solutions like Xen, KVM, Qemu, VMWare, ...&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="81">Frederik Kaputa</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://wiki.centos.org/Events/Fosdem2007?action=AttachFile&amp;do=get&amp;target=openvz-centos.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="11">
      <start>18:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>H.2214</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>RPMforge - Enterprise Linux packaging for CentOS and RHEL</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>CentOS + Fedora</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;RPMforge - Enterprise Linux packaging for CentOS and RHEL.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;RPMforge&amp;#39;s past, presence and future all-in-one presentation.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;RPMforge is a 3rd party repository of RPM packages that finds it roots in individual packaging projects from FreshRPMS (Matthias Saou), Dag Wieers and Dries Verachtert.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A lot of things happened since the very first RPM packages were made against Red Hat Linux and where RPMforge stands today. The advent of Red Hat Enterprise Linux, the replacement of Red Hat Linux by Fedora Linux, the availability of RHEL clones, Fedora Extras and the present dominance of CentOS changed how 3rd party repositories worked and interfaced with communities.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This presentation will give an historical overview of how RPMforge came to be, where it is today and where we are heading to. For current RPMforge users we will touch the subject on how you can contribute and discuss ways to accelerate development.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="111">Dag Wieers</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://wiki.centos.org/Events/Fosdem2007?action=AttachFile&amp;do=get&amp;target=fosdem-2007-rpmforge.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="16">
      <start>16:15</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>AW1.125</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Automated Testing of Debian Package</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Debian</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Automated Testing of Debian Packages: Past, Present and Future&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Quality Assurance plays a very important role in Debian, ensuring that all packages meet a certain quality standard. Due to the high number of&#xA;packages in Debian, it is necessary to perform such tasks in an automated way. This talk will describe two diffferent kinds of tests that were run before the etch release (rebuild of all packages, and installation testing using piuparts), outlining current problems and possible future improvements. It will also discuss what could be done during the lenny release cycle.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="161">Lucas Nussbaum</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://meetings-archive.debian.net/pub/debian-meetings/2007/fosdem/slides/Automated_Testing_of_Debian_Package-Lucas_Nussbaum/fosdem07-auttest.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
          <link href="http://meetings-archive.debian.net/pub/debian-meetings/2007/fosdem/ogg_theora/720x576/Automated_Testing_of_Debian_Package-Lucas_Nussbaum.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
          <link href="http://meetings-archive.debian.net/pub/debian-meetings/2007/fosdem/xvid/Automated_Testing_of_Debian_Package-Lucas_Nussbaum_xvid.avi">Video (DIVX)</link>
          <link href="http://meetings-archive.debian.net/pub/debian-meetings/2007/fosdem/ogg_theora/360x288/Automated_Testing_of_Debian_Package-Lucas_Nussbaum.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora/Low quality)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="19">
      <start>17:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.125</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Delta Upgrades without rsync</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Debian</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Apt-get me faster: Delta Upgrades without the Rsync&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the future, a one-line security update or dist-upgrade should mean a smaller download. Existing technologies such as diff, bsdiff, zsync and&#xA;xdelta reduce the amount of data transferred by detecting similarity between two revisions of a binary or source package.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Current methods are restricted to updates between specific versions (pdiff), require heavy server support (rsync), or are adversely affected by the gzip and bzip2 compression used within Debian packages.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A generic solution, &amp;#39;apt-sync&amp;#39;, allows updating the contents of a package between any currently installed version, to the latest, in a bandwidth efficient way.  Based on ideas from &amp;#39;zsync&amp;#39;, the existing compression and &amp;#39;dumb&amp;#39; HTTP mirror network are utilised in a backwards compatible manner; with all computation performed by the client.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Early code produced from Google&amp;#39;s SoC is being low-key tested within Ubuntu and is available in the &amp;#39;apt-sync&amp;#39; package, supported by meta-data on &lt;a href=&#34;http://people.ubuntu.com/~mvo/apt-sync&#34;&gt;people.ubuntu.com/~mvo/apt-sync&lt;/a&gt;.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="191">Michael Vogt</person>
          <person id="192">Paul Sladen</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://meetings-archive.debian.net/pub/debian-meetings/2007/fosdem/slides/Delta_Upgrades_without_rsync-Michael_Vogt+Paul_Sladen/Sladen-Delta-upgrades.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
          <link href="http://meetings-archive.debian.net/pub/debian-meetings/2007/fosdem/ogg_theora/720x576/Delta_Upgrades_without_rsync-Michael_Vogt+Paul_Sladen.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
          <link href="http://meetings-archive.debian.net/pub/debian-meetings/2007/fosdem/xvid/Delta_Upgrades_without_rsync-Michael_Vogt+Paul_Sladen_xvid.avi">Video (DIVX)</link>
          <link href="http://meetings-archive.debian.net/pub/debian-meetings/2007/fosdem/ogg_theora/360x288/Delta_Upgrades_without_rsync-Michael_Vogt+Paul_Sladen.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora/Low quality)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="23">
      <start>15:15</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.125</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Mole -- Infrastructure for Managing Information</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Debian</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This talk describes &amp;#34;mole&amp;#34;, a set of scripts which together comprise infrastructure with which various sorts of information can be managed.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The major properties of mole are:&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; A means to accept submitted information, with optional access control and moderation&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; A means to store both transient and constant information (&amp;#34;data&amp;#34;)&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; A means to retrieve this information quickly and efficiently in both micro-queries and as whole datasets&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; A means to coordinate the generation of information&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;This is very generally spoken mole. To make things a bit more concrete, one example:&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; Mole would accept (by mail, HTTP post, or otherwise) build logs for building source package in current unstable/testing in a standard or rather a specifically tweaked environment&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; It would store it in its database in an efficient form, keeping some configured amount of older versions too&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; It would maintain a list of source packages that don&amp;#39;t have such log yet, or which log is older than a configurable amount of time, and provide worker machines that can do such rebuilding with a todo-list.&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; Mole would automatically keep track such that double work is prevented.&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; Via for example a web interface people can query results of specific packages, but one can also retrieve the full database.&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;This approach is very powerful, because mole &amp;#34;jobs&amp;#34; can be stacked. To continue with the above example, a different job could keep track of such logs that didn&amp;#39;t get &amp;#39;judged&amp;#39; yet, and have a worker judge them for &amp;#34;successful/not-successful&amp;#34;, and store those qualifications in a result table.&#xA;&#xA;Additionally, data-providers do not need to be computer programs, they can also be humans. For example, the job could be &amp;#34;file bugs on failed logs/mark a failed log as &amp;#34;wrongly failed&amp;#34;. Data can also be about non-package things, such as bugs, or mirrors. It can itself also be something else than quality tests, examples would be mere extraction of data such as .desktop files for auto-installers, SLOC-counts for funny statistics, or (user-supplied) screenshots and reviews.&#xA;&#xA;Current implementation is functional, but is still a little bit rough.&#xA;It lacks mostly on documentation, needs some scalability tweaks, and perhaps most importantly, it doesn&amp;#39;t have an easy query interface such as a web interface yet.&#xA;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="231">Jeroen Van Wolffelaar</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://meetings-archive.debian.net/pub/debian-meetings/2007/fosdem/slides/Mole_-_Infrastructure_for_Managing_Information-Jeroen_Van_Wolffelaar/Mole_-_Infrastructure_for_Managing_Information-Jeroen_Van_Wolffelaar.odp">Slides (OOo)</link>
          <link href="http://meetings-archive.debian.net/pub/debian-meetings/2007/fosdem/ogg_theora/720x576/Mole_-_Infrastructure_for_Managing_Information-Jeroen_Van_Wolffelaar.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
          <link href="http://meetings-archive.debian.net/pub/debian-meetings/2007/fosdem/xvid/Mole_-_Infrastructure_for_Managing_Information-Jeroen_Van_Wolffelaar_xvid.avi">Video (DIVX)</link>
          <link href="http://meetings-archive.debian.net/pub/debian-meetings/2007/fosdem/ogg_theora/360x288/Mole_-_Infrastructure_for_Managing_Information-Jeroen_Van_Wolffelaar.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora/Low quality)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="27">
      <start>14:15</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.125</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Testing migration</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Debian</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As member of the Release Team, Luc will give a clearer look on how packages migrate to testing.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He will cover testing migration criteria, blocking and hinting of packages into testing, transitions, freezing, do&amp;#39;s and don&amp;#39;ts for maintainers etc.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description></description>
      <persons>
          <person id="271">Luk Claes</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://meetings-archive.debian.net/pub/debian-meetings/2007/fosdem/ogg_theora/720x576/Testing_migration-Luk_Claes.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
          <link href="http://meetings-archive.debian.net/pub/debian-meetings/2007/fosdem/xvid/Testing_migration-Luk_Claes_xvid.avi">Video (DIVX)</link>
          <link href="http://meetings-archive.debian.net/pub/debian-meetings/2007/fosdem/ogg_theora/360x288/Testing_migration-Luk_Claes.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora/Low quality)</link>
          <link href="http://meetings-archive.debian.net/pub/debian-meetings/2007/fosdem/slides/Testing_migration-Luk_Claes/fosdem.xml">Slides (HTML)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="28">
      <start>18:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.125</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Open Source VoIP with Debian</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Debian</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Companies are seeking to rip out their proprietary phone systems and looking to VoIP to provide an all-in-one, open standards/open source solution.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Of course, for those who don&amp;#39;t want a blue screen of death appearing on their telephone display in the middle of an important sales call, Debian (should be) the platform of choice.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During this session, Pocock will discuss some practical examples of building VoIP solutions on Debian, will look at the reSIProcate stack as a way to integrate SIP features into existing Linux desktop and server applications (with an example that developers can take away and use in their existing&#xA;applications), and will happily take questions on other topics including QoS, Asterisk, SER, Codecs/bandwidth requirements and ENUM.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Depending upon the availability of time and equipment, there may be some practical, hands on experiments/demonstrations of SIP technology.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="281">Daniel Pocock</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://meetings-archive.debian.net/pub/debian-meetings/2007/fosdem/slides/Open_Source_VoIP_with_Debian-Daniel_Pocock/fosdem-2007.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
          <link href="http://meetings-archive.debian.net/pub/debian-meetings/2007/fosdem/ogg_theora/720x576/Open_Source_VoIP_with_Debian-Daniel_Pocock.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
          <link href="http://meetings-archive.debian.net/pub/debian-meetings/2007/fosdem/xvid/Open_Source_VoIP_with_Debian-Daniel_Pocock_xvid.avi">Video (DIVX)</link>
          <link href="http://meetings-archive.debian.net/pub/debian-meetings/2007/fosdem/ogg_theora/360x288/Open_Source_VoIP_with_Debian-Daniel_Pocock.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora/Low quality)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="29">
      <start>17:15</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>Janson</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Donators Return</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Opening/Closing talks</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Giveaways for the people who donated.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Prizes and giveaways announcement session for &lt;a href=&#34;http://fosdem.org/2007/support/donate&#34;&gt;people who donated&lt;/a&gt;.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="291">FOSDEM</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="31">
      <start>16:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.126</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Analysing Embedded Memory Use</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Embedded</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Analysing Embedded Memory Use: Introduction to Exmap-Console Tools&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How much memory is *really* used by what and how? On the Linux desktop, the not very widely known Exmap tool has for some time provided exhaustive answers these questions, breaking down memory use to individual symbols in an executable or a linked library, while separating mapped memory from unmapped, shared from unshared, and even calculating each application&amp;#39;s effective portion of the shared.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Exmap-console is a suite of command-line tools, developed at OpenedHand Ltd, that bring the power of Exmap to embedded Linux; it includes an interactive console client, a server application for remote sessions, and a daemon for automated logging. The talk will provide an overview of the tools and a demonstration of their use.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="311">Tomas Frydrych</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="../../slides/devrooms/embedded/exmap/slide-00.html">Slides (HTML)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="33">
      <start>15:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.126</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>HomeSIP</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Embedded</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.enseirb.fr/cosynux/HomeSIP/&#34;&gt;HomeSIP Project&lt;/a&gt;: Using open source SIP stack for Home Automation&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For the next decade, we‘ll witness the convergence between 3 sciences: computer science, telecommunications and microelectronics.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many communicating embedded systems are around us. More and more of them will be present at home for home automation.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The HomeSIP project consists to develop an open platform for Home Automation using SIP (Session Initiation Protocol) protocol. The SIP protocol is a well known protocol for VoIP (Voice Over IP). This talk will present the HomeSIP project. The SIP protocol will be described in a Home Automation point of view and compared to other protocols like SNMP, HTTP used for controlling embedded systems.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The HomeSIP infrastructure will be presented: choice of an open source SIP stack (GNU oSIP/eXoSIP), developed Linux based SIP gateways, sensors networks...&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Finally, we’ll present a new DSL (Domain Specific Language) language for developing new services for Home Automation.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="331">Patrice Kadionik</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="../../slides/devrooms/embedded/fosdem2007_kadionik.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
          <link href="../../slides/devrooms/embedded/fosdem2007_kadionik.odp">Slides (OOo)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="37">
      <start>17:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.126</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>OpenMoko</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Embedded</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openmoko.com/&#34;&gt;OpenMoko&lt;/a&gt;, Exploration of an Emotion&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This talk will shed light on the reasons for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openmoko.com/&#34;&gt;OpenMoko&lt;/a&gt; and explain the ideas behind it.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tell more about how its implementation, the architecture and the tools that have been chosen. Further background on the future of the projects and the related dreams will be given, and also the community involvement will be presented. This of course includes the way how the OpenMoko projects sees the community and how it hopes normal people  and developers alike will get involved. After all the real power emerges from the interaction of all the users of &amp;#34;freed phones.&amp;#34;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="371">Sean Moss-Pultz</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="../../slides/devrooms/embedded/Sean_Moss-Pultz-OpenMoko.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="38">
      <start>14:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.126</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Porting device drivers to 2.6</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Embedded</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Porting device drivers for the 2.6 kernel, the new driver framework.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this talk we will look into the challenges and contradictions OS designers and developers face. The first group needs to maintain order and sense in the kernel structure while the other has to get the things working.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We will look at the compromises made in the reality of the Linux kernel. Next we will overview the bus and driver model of the 2.6 kernel, also looking at the development of sysfs and the vexed relationship with proc and udev/devfs. Also addressed will behow to deal with programmable devices (such as FPGA&amp;#39;s) and how they fit (or not) in the OS&amp;#39;s bus and device hierarchy.&#xA;Finally an example (namely the SMCs91c96i driver will be taken as an example and look at actually how to port working  driver code into the 2.6 series.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="381">Craig Duffy</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="../../slides/devrooms/embedded/Craig_Duffy_Porting_drivers.odp">Slides (OOo)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="40">
      <start>18:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.126</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>RTLinux into an FPGA</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Embedded</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Description of the work done to port the RTLinux-free microkernel to the uClinux/Microblaze architecture, enabling hard real-time programming in an FPGA based system.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Microblaze is a soft processor which can be added into an FPGA design, just using the IP block offered by Xilinx. The combination of an FPGA and a microprocessor running an operating system like uClinux offers great flexibility to embedded designs. &#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With this enviroment, the critical part of the system can be resolved using the programmable logic array, and the functionalities offered by the operating system facilitates other tasks such as data storage, communications, graphical interfaces, etc. However, the border between critical tasks and the rest of the system is not fully clear, and sometimes responsiveness and accuracy are needed in the operating system.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We describe the work done to port the RTLinux-free microkernel to the uClinux/Microblaze architecture, enabling hard real-time programming in an FPGA based system.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="401">Alejandro Lucero</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="../../slides/devrooms/embedded/Alejandro_lucero_FPGA.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
          <link href="../../slides/devrooms/embedded/Alejandro_lucero_FPGA.odp">Slides (OOo)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="44">
      <start>17:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>H.2214</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Fedora Directory Server</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>CentOS + Fedora</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jens will present the Fedora Directory Server.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description></description>
      <persons>
          <person id="441">Jens Kuehnel</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="47">
      <start>15:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>H.2214</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Introduction to Fedora</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>CentOS + Fedora</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction of Fedora and what the project will present at the booth&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description></description>
      <persons>
          <person id="471">Chitlesh Goorah</person>
          <person id="472">Max Spevack</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://fedoraproject.org/wiki/FUDCon/FUDConBrussels2007?action=AttachFile&amp;do=get&amp;target=ChitSlide-mspevack.odp">Slides (OOo)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="53">
      <start>16:00</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>Chavanne</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>GEGL</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Desktop Applications</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://pippin.gimp.org/gegl/&#34;&gt;GEGL&lt;/a&gt; is a graph based image processing framework.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The presentation will introduce the capabilities of the framework and how the public API is used, as well as the current state of the internal architecture and possible directions for future optimizations and enhancements.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This talk will present core aspects of &lt;a href=&#34;http://pippin.gimp.org/gegl/&#34;&gt;GEGL&lt;/a&gt;, a graph based image processing and compositing framework.&#xA;GEGL allows non-destructive editing, high dynamic range, large images and other features the current GIMP engine does not handle.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In earlier talks about GEGL Øyvind has been focusing on the past and the future. Now is the time to talk about the current state of GEGL. GEGLs capabilities are currently gaining strength and the public API is reaching stability.&#xA;He will talk about how to embed GEGL in an application or script to do image processing tasks and will also give an explanation of GEGLs inner workings and plug-in system.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="531">Øyvind Kolås</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="../../slides/maintracks/gegl.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
          <link href="http://video.fosdem.org/2007/FOSDEM2007-GEGL.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="54">
      <start>17:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.124</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Gentoo/Alt:Prefix Project</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Gentoo</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Gentoo Prefixed portage.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, Fabian will give an overview of the Gentoo Prefixed Portage project.                                                                                                               &#xA;&lt;/p&gt;                                                                                                                               &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mac OS X, Solaris, HPUX, etc. are all non-Linux operating systems. Fedora, SuSE, Debian ... even Gentoo Linux might be installed on your                                                          workstation at work or university. What do both have in commmon? The Gentoo Prefixed Portage project targets them.                                                                                  &#xA;&lt;/p&gt;                                                                                                                               &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fabian will briefly discuss the rationales behind the Prefixed Portage project, and sketch its characteristics.&#xA;In the main body of the talk, he will discuss the changes made to Portage for prefix, and the ebuilds                                                         that are used.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="541">Fabian Groffen</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="58">
      <start>18:00</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>AW1.124</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Gentoo&#39;s future</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Gentoo</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;General discussion about Gentoo&amp;#39;s future.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For all developers.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="581">Dimitry Bradt</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="59">
      <start>14:30</start>
      <duration>01:30</duration>
      <room>AW1.124</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Gentoo Hardened</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Gentoo</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Gentoo Hardened - the hardened toolchain and the security perspective of the Gentoo Linux distribution.&#xA;The current status of security measures available to the Gentoo Linux distribution.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The talk will describe and discuss the security measures available to users of the Gentoo Linux distribution and the work of the Gentoo developers to enhance and integrate the available solutions for the GNU/Linux operating system and userland.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="591">Alexander Gabert</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="63">
      <start>16:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.124</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Introduction to SELinux</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Gentoo</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction to SELinux&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The talk will be part historical background talking about authorization from early UNIX days to now and part technical describing important SELinux concepts and how they can help secure servers and desktop machines.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="631">Bryan Østergaard</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="65">
      <start>14:00</start>
      <duration>00:30</duration>
      <room>AW1.124</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Gentoo</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the Gentoo devroom&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description></description>
      <persons>
          <person id="651">Dimitry Bradt</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="67">
      <start>14:30</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>H.1302</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Gnome BuildBrigade</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>GNOME</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Build Brigade is an effort to automate discovery and reporting of Gnome build errors and to make testing of the development version easy for everyone&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description></description>
      <persons>
          <person id="671">Juan José Sánchez Penas</person>
          <person id="672">Iago Toral Quiroga</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="69">
      <start>18:15</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>H.1302</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>GNOME apps with Scheme</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>GNOME</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the course of work on some other projects, Andy managed to make a reasonably comprehensive set of bindings between the GNOME libraries and the Guile dialect of Scheme, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gnu.org/software/guile-gnome/&#34;&gt;guile-gnome&lt;/a&gt;. Andy will show people with a curiosity for languages how you can hack GNOME in Scheme. It&amp;#39;s a bit off-beat, and quite refreshing compared to other more well-known languages.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description></description>
      <persons>
          <person id="691">Andy Wingo</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="71">
      <start>15:15</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>H.1302</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>What&#39;s new in GStreamer</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>GNOME</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This talk will revolve around the new features and improvements that have appeared in &lt;a href=&#34;http://gstreamer.freedesktop.org/&#34;&gt;GStreamer&lt;/a&gt; over the past 6 months, and what new ideas are being currently discussed and designed.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During the ongoing process of developing the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pitivi.org/&#34;&gt;PiTIVi&lt;/a&gt; video editor, Edward Hervey got to discover, love and finally hack on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://gstreamer.freedesktop.org/&#34;&gt;GStreamer multimedia framework&lt;/a&gt;. In fact he spends most of this time hacking in GStreamer, fixing core issues and bringing new functionalities.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="711">Edward Hervey</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="72">
      <start>17:30</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>H.1302</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>gtkmm</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>GNOME</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Developing GNOME applications using gtkmm&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;gtkmm is the official C++ interface for the popular GUI library GTK+. It is designed to ensure typesafe programming and yet let programmers enjoy&#xA;the neat model of the Gtk+ framework.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This talk will present Gtkmm and the so called modern programming techniques associated to the C++ language that are available to GNOME application programmers today.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It will focus on techniques to write safer GNOME applications and libraries in a modular manner.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="721">Dodji Seketeli</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="74">
      <start>16:45</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>H.1302</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Developing GNOME through marketing and outreach</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>GNOME</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Developing GNOME through marketing and outreach.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description></description>
      <persons>
          <person id="741">Dave Neary</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="75">
      <start>16:00</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>H.1302</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>tinymail</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>GNOME</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tinymail is a library (or framework, if you like the buzzwords) for developing mobile applications with E-mail functionality.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Usually but not limited to Mail User Agents (MUA). The framework provides components that aid the developer with the user interface but of course also with the connectivity and the caching of messages.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For more information about tinymail consult its website at &lt;a href=&#34;http://tinymail.org/&#34;&gt;tinymail.org&lt;/a&gt;.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="751">Philip Van Hoof</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="76">
      <start>14:15</start>
      <duration>00:15</duration>
      <room>H.1302</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>GNOME</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the GNOME developer room&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description></description>
      <persons>
          <person id="761">Christophe Fergeau</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="78">
      <start>16:00</start>
      <duration>02:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.115</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>3rd Party Solutions within GNUstep</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>OpenGroupware + GNUstep</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Developer Workshop: What to do with 3rd Party Solutions within the GNUstep Community?&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The goal of this workshop is to discuss questions dealing with 3rd party solutions and GNUstep and to summarize the results. At the beginning we may identify projects which seem to reinvent the wheel. Such projects are those implementing add-ons which have been developed before – logging functionality is a good example for this. Also, we may focus projects (re-) implementing GNUstep base functionality, like e.g. mySTEP. Then, having these projects figured out we may elaborate the potential reasons behind.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By starting to identify reasons for &amp;#34;duplicating&amp;#34; code we may shift the discussion to a different perspective and ask ourself, what GNUstep brings to the application programmer? Especially we may work out the requirements of the “typical” GNUstep application programmer.  Collecting all information, thus bringing the potential reasons for “duplicated” codes, plus the capabilities of and the requirements for GNUstep altogether, we may then find out approaches for the handling of 3rd party solutions within the GNUstep community.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since this session is meant as a workshop, the abstract presented hereby should be regarded as a collection of hints and all developers are warmly invited to actively participate in the discussion. The session will be moderated and organized by Helge Hess and Oliver Langer.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="781">Oliver Langer</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="83">
      <start>14:15</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>AW1.115</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>GNUstep-make</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>OpenGroupware + GNUstep</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;GNUstep development tools: GNUstep-make&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description></description>
      <persons>
          <person id="831">Nicola Pero</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="84">
      <start>15:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.115</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Project Manager IDE</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>OpenGroupware + GNUstep</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;GNUstep development tools: &lt;a href=&#34;http://home.gna.org/pmanager/&#34;&gt;Project Manager IDE&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description></description>
      <persons>
          <person id="841">Sašo Kiselkov</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="91">
      <start>14:30</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>AW1.105</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Jabber 101</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Jabber</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A fast-paced overview of Jabber technologies: where they came from, how they work, how you can use them, and where they&amp;#39;re going.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The focus will be on information that developers and sysadmins need to get things done with Jabber.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="911">Peter Saint-Andre</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="92">
      <start>16:00</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>AW1.105</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Beyond JSON</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Jabber</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Beyond JSON: Interoperable RIAs over XMPP (ROX)&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The hacker-friendly documentation generated by the Jabber standards community solves most of the issues faced by distributed application developers. &#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rich Internet Application (RIA) hackers (who may have been using JSON, Comet or AJAX for browser-server communications) can use XMPP to build on top of the wealth of existing Jabber applications and to interoperate with RIAs produced by other developers. RIAs can connect to Jabber servers via a choice of two browser-friendly HTTP streaming standards.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;BOAH extends the Comet technique, while BOSH is a novel mature protocol that passes through more proxies and enables efficient cross-domain streaming.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="921">Ian Paterson</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="98">
      <start>16:45</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>AW1.105</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Tigase</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Jabber</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tigase.org/&#34;&gt;Tigase&lt;/a&gt; is a Jabber server written in Java.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This presentation will go into the project goals and its current status. It will highlight the technical challenges encountered during development, while going over the server&amp;#39;s design.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Finally the future plans of the project and directions in the short term will be presented.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="981">Artur Hefczyc</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="99">
      <start>15:15</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>AW1.105</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Virtual Presence with Jabber</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Jabber</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.virtual-presence.org/&#34;&gt;Virtual Presence&lt;/a&gt; makes people aware of each other on Web pages. They meet, chat, and voip wherever they go on the Web. Jabber proved to be the perfect foundation for such a large scale virtual presence network.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The presentation explains what a VP client is and how it uses Jabber. It explains the VP protocol extensions (JEP-0151) and other important details of the Jabber based VP network.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="991">Heiner Wolf</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="100">
      <start>14:15</start>
      <duration>00:15</duration>
      <room>AW1.105</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Jabber</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the Jabber developer room at FOSDEM.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description></description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1001">Ralph Meijer</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="101">
      <start>17:30</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>AW1.105</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Yate</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Jabber</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://yate.null.ro/&#34;&gt;Yate&lt;/a&gt;, Yet Another Telephony Engine, is a next-generation telephony engine.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While currently focused on Voice over Internet Protocol (VoIP) and PSTN, the power of Yate lies in its ability to be easily extended.&#xA;Voice, video, data and instant messaging can all be unified under Yate&amp;#39;s flexible routing engine, maximizing communications efficiency and minimizing infrastructure costs for businesses.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This talk is about the interoperability between &lt;a href=&#34;http://yate.null.ro/&#34;&gt;Yate&lt;/a&gt; and Jabber server &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tigase.org/&#34;&gt;Tigase&lt;/a&gt;.&#xA;Yate supports Jingle protocol and together with Tigase can be used to build tomorrow&amp;#39;s open telephony networks.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1011">Diana Cionoiu</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="102">
      <start>14:15</start>
      <duration>01:30</duration>
      <room>H.2213</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>GNU Classpath Runtime Rumble</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>GNU Classpath + OpenJDK DevJam</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Heavyweight champions of various GNU Classpath based virtual machines will each give a short presentation on what makes their runtime special and fun to work with.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; What cool things they have been doing this last year.&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; Their plans for next year.&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; What other runtimes can learn from their experiences. &#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; And how the GNU Classpath community at large (and OpenJDK in the future) can help with that.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1021">Robert Lougher</person>
          <person id="1022">Ian Rogers</person>
          <person id="1023">Christian Thalinger</person>
          <person id="1024">Tom Tromey</person>
          <person id="1025">Dalibor Topic</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="ftp://ftp.cs.man.ac.uk/pub/apt/presentations/irogers_fosdem07.ppt">Slides (Powerpoint)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="104">
      <start>16:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>H.2213</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>GNU Classpath Last Year &amp; Next Year</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>GNU Classpath + OpenJDK DevJam</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Open session giving an overview of last years work on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gnu.org/software/classpath/&#34;&gt;GNU Classpath&lt;/a&gt; library (and given time some demos).&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After a short overview of the various free stacks, libraries, compilers, tools and runtimes this session is mostly open discussion about what work remains to be done and how to integrate the various efforts better.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;GNU Classpath hackers will tell about their current work, their plans and priorities for the next year, and how others can help. We will have a discussion on how to maintain our core values (freedom, coverage, fun &amp;amp; innovation). Our commitment to our community, users and projects and how to make it easy to adopt and collaborate together with GNU Classpath and OpenJDK and how to help also the smaller projects with less resources to adopt the new innovation (coordinating new VM and Platform interfaces, etc.)&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since this is an open session &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:mark@klomp.org&#34;&gt;ideas for other work items are welcome&lt;/a&gt;.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1041">Mark Wielaard</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="107">
      <start>17:00</start>
      <duration>00:30</duration>
      <room>H.1301</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>KDE Documentation</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>KDE</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;KDE Documentation: What we do ... and what we want.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The KDE Documentation team will give an overview of what they are currently doing and what the plans are for KDE 4.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1071">Sander Koning</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="112">
      <start>14:00</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>H.1301</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Semantic KDE</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>KDE</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Semantic KDE - Advanced metadata in KDE with Nepomuk.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Nepomuk-KDE project aims to recreate the way metadata is handled throughout the KDE desktop. Semantic annotation of resources is only the beginning.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;NEPOMUK-KDE is a sub-project of the Semantic-Desktop project Nepomuk which aims to provide a full implementation of the standards and APIs defined in Nepomuk on the KDE Desktop. As a sub-project of Nepomuk the two main issues are the maintenance and intensive usage of metadata throughout the desktop &#xA;and powerful peer-to-peer collaboration techiques.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the first phase of the NEPOMUK-KDE project the focus lies on the metadata part. There are basicly three kinds of metadata to be found on the desktop: &#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; Metadata that can be found in files stored on the local harddisk like tag information in audio files, timestamps, or simple indexed text. This metadata can be extracted and indexed at any time and is exactly the type of information current desktop search projects like Beagle or Strigi are based on.&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; Metadata created manually by the user. In the most simple case this can be a comment to a file or an email. But it could also mean the grouping of several resources under one topic and so on.&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; The most interesting type of metadata is, however, the kind that cannot be extracted easily by an indexer and is not generated by the user manually. &#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;This includes for example the url of a file that is downloaded from the internet. Once saved on the local harddisk this information is lost. The same &#xA;goes for the (rather popular) example of email attachments: Once an email attachment is saved to the local harddisk its connection to the email and &#xA;with it the connection to the sender is lost. These are just two examples relating to the source of files. There are many more.&#xA;&#xA;The goal of the NEPOMUK-KDE project is to create facilities to allow each KDE application to take advantage of this metadata. That means that a KDE &#xA;application can easily create new metadata, search metadata, search relations between resources based on metadata, and so on.&#xA;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1121">Jos van den Oever</person>
          <person id="1122">Stéphane Laurière</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://www.kde.org/kdeslides/fosdem2007/2007-02-vandenoever-kde_semantic.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="113">
      <start>15:00</start>
      <duration>00:30</duration>
      <room>H.1301</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Strigi desktop integration</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>KDE</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Strigi desktop integration: how to access Strigi features.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Strigi, the fastest and smallest desktop search engine, provides fast searches and good metadata extraction capabilities. It will be used by the&#xA;next KDE, but it can be easily integrated in other programs.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Modern humans are using more and more data every day. Keeping data organized is becoming insufficient, so finding and filtering documents&#xA;have become key tasks in modern operating systems. The traditional unix tools find, grep and locate do no longer suffice for a number of&#xA;reasons: The amounts of data have grown more than data access speeds, many document formats are too complex to handle by simple tools and&#xA;relations between different types of data are becoming more important for a convenient user experience. Strigi introduces a new way of looking&#xA;at metadata and file formats that enables the creation of very efficient tools for improving the way users handle their data. It does so by using&#xA;simple C++ code with very few dependencies.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Strigi&amp;#39;s features can be easily integrated by other programs using two different interfaces: socket and DBus. The last one can be considered&#xA;the best choice since there are lot of DBus bindings that make possible to interact with Strigi using different programming&#xA;languages. DBus inter-process communication system will be used by KDE4 and is actually used by Gnome. Moreover, DBus bindings exists for&#xA;lot of programming languages. Thanks to this Strigi can be easily integrated in different window manager and inside programs written in&#xA;languages different from C++.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;KDE developers can also take advantage from Strigi&amp;#39;s JStreams: a set of classes for fast access to archive files. In fact Strigi defines a&#xA;dedicated KIO Slave for JStreams, this can be easily used by other programs, making archives access faster.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This presentation will show how the current Strigi clients interact with the daemon, how to communicate with Strigi and, most important of&#xA;all, how other projects can benefit too accessing Strigi.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1131">Flavio Castelli</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://www.kde.org/kdeslides/fosdem2007/2007-02-flaviocastelli-strigi_desktop_integration.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
          <link href="http://www.kde.org/kdeslides/fosdem2007/2007-02-flaviocastelli-strigi_desktop_integration.odp">Slides (OOo)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="115">
      <start>16:00</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>Janson</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Linux Kernel</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Kernel</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Andrew will present the current trends in Linux kernel development.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Andrew will present a broad look at the trends in recent changes in the Linux kernel: what areas of kernel functionality are people working on, and what changes can we expect to see over the next year ?&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This feature-by-feature walk-through will be tied to an examination of the motivations of the kernel contributors: why do particular individuals and organizations choose particular things to work upon ?&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He will also examine areas of the kernel which are arguably suffering from some neglect, the reasons for this and some possible corrective actions&#xA;which might be taken.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Andrew will finish with a discussion of the importance of individual testers to the kernel development effort, as well as a look at the steps which a&#xA;kernel tester should take to maximize the effectiveness of his or her contribution to the kernel.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1151">Andrew Morton</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="../../slides/maintracks/linux_kernel.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
          <link href="http://video.fosdem.org/2007/FOSDEM2007-LinuxKernel.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="116">
      <start>15:00</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>Janson</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>LinuxBIOS</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Kernel</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://linuxbios.org/&#34;&gt;LinuxBIOS&lt;/a&gt; - building a BIOS for fun and not-profit.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Linux BIOS replaces the normal BIOS found on PCs and other machines.&#xA;The BIOS boot and setup is eliminated and replaced by a very simple initialization phase, followed by a gunzip of a Linux kernel.&#xA;The Linux kernel is then started and from there on the boot proceeds as normal.&#xA;Amongst many other things, it provides a very fast boot time: 3 seconds from power-on to Linux console&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ronald started the &lt;a href=&#34;http://linuxbios.org/&#34;&gt;LinuxBIOS&lt;/a&gt; project in 1999, with the simple goal of building a specialized BIOS for supercomputers.&#xA;Since that time, the LinuxBIOS project has seen the usage grow by a factor of 10 each year, to a projected usage of well over 10 million in 2007, and 100 million in 2008.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With the advent of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://laptop.org/&#34;&gt;OLPC project&lt;/a&gt;, there is enough critical mass to design hardware as it should be designed, and in turn, build a BIOS as it ought to be built.&#xA;For example, the OLPC will not use badly designed standards such as ACPI -- there is no need to.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, Ronald will discuss:&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;some of the early history of LinuxBIOS, as a motivation for why it is designed the way it is;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what he learned in building a free BIOS,&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;including knowledge that was lost but was rediscovered;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;issues he faces in dealing with vendors&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;interesting things you can do when you own the BIOS&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;the work Google is supporting&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;what the future holds&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1161">Ronald G Minnich</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://video.fosdem.org/2007/FOSDEM2007-LinuxBios.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="117">
      <start>13:00</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>Lameere</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>LPI Certifications</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>LPI Certification</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The culmination of LPI&amp;#39;s certification program with the launch of the enterprise Level 3 and a summary of the existing LPIC program.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Topics of the presentation:&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; Linux Professional Institute (LPI) - aims and functions&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; The concepts and details of the certifications of LPI&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; Objectives LPIC-1 and 2&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; Sample questions and simulations&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; Dealing with sample questions, technique of questions&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; Concrete samples live at a Linux system&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; How to prepare for an LPI exam&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; Scheme of the new Level 3 exams 301 and 302&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; Topics, detailed objectives and sample questions of the exams 301 und 302&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1171">Klaus Behrla</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="118">
      <start>14:00</start>
      <duration>01:30</duration>
      <room>Lameere</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>LPI exam session 1</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>LPI Certification</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;LPI Exam session #1&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;http://fosdem.org/2007/lpi&#34;&gt;http://fosdem.org/2007/lpi&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1181">Klaus Behrla</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="119">
      <start>16:00</start>
      <duration>01:30</duration>
      <room>Lameere</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>LPI exam session 2</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>LPI Certification</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;LPI Exam session #2&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;http://fosdem.org/2007/lpi&#34;&gt;http://fosdem.org/2007/lpi&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1191">Klaus Behrla</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="127">
      <start>14:20</start>
      <duration>00:15</duration>
      <room>Ferrer</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>CMake</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Lightning Talks</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A lightning talk that will quickly introduce the software development process with &#xA;CMake, CTest, Dart and CPack.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CMake is a cross platform buildsystem for Linux, *BSD, QNX, Windows, OS X and &#xA;others, featuring system introspection, support for Makefiles and project &#xA;files e.g. for KDevelop and Xcode and of course building apps and libs.&#xA;CMake features tight integration with CTest and Dart, which form together a &#xA;powerful and easy-to-use software quality system. Dart is a central server &#xA;which collects the results from Nightly and Continuous builds, including &#xA;regular unit tests and more. &#xA;Newly introduced is CPack, a tool for generating distribution packages for all &#xA;supported platforms.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1271">Alexander Neundorf</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="../../slides/lightningtalks/CMake.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="128">
      <start>17:20</start>
      <duration>00:15</duration>
      <room>Ferrer</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>db4o</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Lightning Talks</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A lightning talk about db4o, an object database, and its open source company.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this talk db4o will be introduced, an open source object database, and&#xA;it&amp;#39;s licensing model. The talk will also be about how we work as an open source&#xA;company, where all the contributors are spread around the world.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;About db4o:&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;db4o, a native object persistence solution for Java and .net.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1281">Jb Evain</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="../../slides/lightningtalks/db4o.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="129">
      <start>14:00</start>
      <duration>00:15</duration>
      <room>Ferrer</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Freedom Task Force</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Lightning Talks</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A lightning talk about Free Sofware licensing and the FTF.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The talk will explain the type of licence used in the Free Software&#xA;eco-system.  It will examine the legal questions involved in a project&#xA;with multiple participants, describing what possibilities and dangers&#xA;exist in mixing code from different sources.  The talk will cover&#xA;best-practice models for developers and projects that adopt Free&#xA;Software, and will examine how Free Software licensing can be used to&#xA;produce commercial products within the context of existing business&#xA;models.  The services and reasoning behind the creation of FSFE&amp;#39;s&#xA;Freedom Task Force (FTF) will then be explained.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;About the Free Software Foundation Europe:&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The FTF is FSFE&amp;#39;s licensing project.  It provides licensing education,&#xA;fiduciary services for projects, and works in partnership with&#xA;gpl-violations.org to deal with licence violations in the European&#xA;arena.  The FTF website is located here:&#xA;http://fsfeurope.org/ftf&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The FTF is an infrastructure project for the Free Software eco-system.&#xA;We have a network of technical and legal experts that can help&#xA;individuals, projects and businesses understand Free Software licensing&#xA;and the opportunities that it presents.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have two press releases that give more detailed information about the&#xA;FTF, see Links section.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1291">Shane Coughlan</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="../../slides/lightningtalks/FTF.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="130">
      <start>15:00</start>
      <duration>00:15</duration>
      <room>Ferrer</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Instlux</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Lightning Talks</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A lightning talk about Instlux, an installation program for windows, that installs linux.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Presentation of the project:&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; What it is&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; How it works&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; How it is implemented&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; How to contribute&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; Future plans&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;i&gt;About Instlux:&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;&lt;dd&gt;&#xA;&lt;/dd&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;Instlux is a collaborative project hosted on sourceforge that&#xA;simplifies the Linux installation on a Windows system.&#xA;&#xA;Its main contribution is that it makes the installation easier by&#xA;avoiding the BIOS configuration step. That is, with instlux, a Windows&#xA;user can install linux without configuring the BIOS and so without&#xA;booting from the DVD/CDROM.&#xA;&#xA;Instlux has been translated into 20 languages: albanian, catalan, czech,&#xA;danish, dutch, finnish, french, german, indonesian, italian, lithuanian,&#xA;polish, portuguese, brasilian, romanian, spanish, swedish, turkish, ... &#xA;&#xA;It supports two distributions, Ubuntu and OpenSuSE.&#xA;&#xA;Instlux is one year old. During this year, it has been downloaded 50000&#xA;times. There are 40 pages that link to the project web page, and more&#xA;than 127000 references to it[1].&#xA;&#xA;&lt;i&gt;Opinions about it:&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;&amp;#34;This is an amazingly cool idea. &amp;#34; by Cody Somerville, Canadian ubuntu&#xA;team member, Xubuntu users admin, Ubuntu marketing team&#xA;&#xA;&amp;#34;Instlux the fifth columnist .exe file that installs GNU/Linux&#xA;(Ubuntu, OpenSUSE and other distros to come) from MS Windows. A&#xA;must-have in less than five years that is already built and working&amp;#34; by&#xA;Quim Gil, organizer of the Guadec 2006 and Maemo product manager at&#xA;Nokia&amp;#39;s OSSO Team.&#xA;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1301">Jordi Massaguer</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="../../slides/lightningtalks/Instlux.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="131">
      <start>15:40</start>
      <duration>00:15</duration>
      <room>Ferrer</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>LiVES</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Lightning Talks</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A lightningtalk and demo about LiVES, an open source Video Editing System.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The lightning talk will demonstrate the features of LiVES and show how it can be used both by VJ&amp;#39;s and digital video artists to produce eye-catching and spectacular results.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;About LiVES:&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;LiVES is a Video Editing System. It allows both realtime and non-realtime manipulation of video and audio. It can be controlled either through the user-friendly interface or remotely over a network. It has the capability of working with almost any video format. It can also be easily extended through a system of plugins, utilising open standards.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1311">Gabriel Finch</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="../../slides/lightningtalks/LiVES.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="135">
      <start>17:40</start>
      <duration>00:15</duration>
      <room>Ferrer</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>MoulinWiki</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Lightning Talks</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A lightning talk on Moulin, an offline version of Wikipedia.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A short description of what your lightning talk will be about:&#xA;I&amp;#39;d like to explain the life-cycle of a project – specifically, the&#xA;moulin project – from its conception, through its planning, financing,&#xA;and development, up to its release into the community (local and&#xA;global), through an NGO such as Geekcorps&amp;#39; perpective.&#xA;I&amp;#39;d also like to add how an organization such as Geekcorps designs and&#xA;delivers its projects for communities in the developing world. &#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;About MoulinWiki:&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;moulin is a standalone (and live CD), offline version of the Wikipedia&#xA;encyclopaedia specifically tailored for developing world.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1351">Renaud Gaudin</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="../../slides/lightningtalks/MoulinWiki.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="137">
      <start>17:00</start>
      <duration>00:15</duration>
      <room>Ferrer</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>MySQL</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Lightning Talks</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A lightning talk about what&amp;#39;s new at MySQL AB&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This talk will provide you with quick updates about what&amp;#39;s going on at MySQL AB&#xA;with regards to new products, updates to existing ones as well as ongoing&#xA;community activities and offerings.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;About MySQL:&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;MySQL AB is the company that develops and markets the MySQL Server and related&#xA;Open Source products. As part of the LAMP stack, MySQL is quite popular as an&#xA;essential component of today&amp;#39;s OSS information technology infrastructure.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1371">Lenz Grimmer</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="../../slides/lightningtalks/MySQL.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="138">
      <start>16:20</start>
      <duration>00:15</duration>
      <room>Ferrer</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Nagios Plugins</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Lightning Talks</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A lightning talk about Nagios Plugins, and how to write one.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nagios Plugins is the project that creates the core plugins that work with Nagios, the world&amp;#39;s most popular open source monitoring system. Ton Voon explains how these two projects fit together and demonstrates how to write a great plugin in under 8 minutes.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;About Nagiosplug:&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nagios Plugins&amp;#39; mission is to provide the best cross unix plugins for the Nagios monitoring system.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1381">Ton Voon</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="../../slides/lightningtalks/NagiosPlugins.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="141">
      <start>15:20</start>
      <duration>00:15</duration>
      <room>Ferrer</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>OpenWengo</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Lightning Talks</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A lightning talk about &amp;#34;OpenWengo - VoIP and communication over IP in&#xA;the participative age&amp;#34;.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#34;OpenWengo - VoIP and communication over IP in&#xA;the participative age&amp;#34;. Dave Neary will present the OpenWengo project,&#xA;our community, and what&amp;#39;s interesting and passionate about working on&#xA;the bleeding edge of VoIP.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;About OpenWengo:&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;OpenWengo is a free software project to&#xA;create a unified communication over IP program. The WengoPhone is a&#xA;standards-based softphone, videophone and IM client with a growing&#xA;community.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1411">Dave Neary</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="../../slides/lightningtalks/OpenWengo.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="143">
      <start>14:40</start>
      <duration>00:15</duration>
      <room>Ferrer</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Pandora Free Monitoring System</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Lightning Talks</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A lightning talk about what Pandora FMS is, how it works, and how it is used.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The talk will show how Pandora works and what things could be done with Pandora FMS, that´s to say, show Pandora FMS to everybody and if anybody is interested, we (all the team would go to Brussels) will give him/her further information. We will be available to explain him/her whatever he/she wants to know about our project. The demostration is not going to be a 15 minutes of command-line, not at all, actually, Pandora is so easy because it can be managed from a Web Console.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;About Pandora FMS:&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pandora FMS is a monitoring tool that allows a system administrator to visually analise the status and efficiency of Operating Systems, Servers, Applications and Hardware Systems - such as firewalls,proxies, databases, Web servers, tunnelling servers, routers, switches, processes, services, remote access&#xA;servers, etc. - all integrated into an open and distributed architecture. Pandora can be implemented over many operating system, with specific agents for each platform. Pandora can also monitor any TCP/IP hardware system, as load balancers, routers, switches, printers, etc.&#xA;Everything of the above is easily controlled by a Web Console, making the procces of monitorizing a box so easy and intuitive at all.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pandora FMS is being used in loads of big companys in Spain, such as Red Electrica de España (Which is one of largest companys in the country and where all the spanish electricity is managed).&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1431">Manuel Arostegui</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="../../slides/lightningtalks/Pandora.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="144">
      <start>16:00</start>
      <duration>00:15</duration>
      <room>Ferrer</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Parted</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Lightning Talks</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A lightning talk about Parted, its current and future features.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Discussion of current features in the 1.8.x release tree and plans for that branch&amp;#39;s future releases.  Cover the plans and goals for the parted 2.0 release, including filesystem VFS layer, improved exception handling, and other language bindings.  Explain how parted is used in various projects and how users can contribute. &#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;About Parted:&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;GNU parted is an open source disk partitioning and filesystem creation utility.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1441">David Cantrell</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="../../slides/lightningtalks/Parted.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="149">
      <start>16:40</start>
      <duration>00:15</duration>
      <room>Ferrer</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Wt</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Lightning Talks</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A lightningtalk about Wt, a C++ library to develop web applications.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After a short introduction to the Wt library basics and the problems&#xA;it solves, we will demonstrate by example how straight-forward the&#xA;development of cross-browser portable web applications can be.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;About Wt:&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wt (pronounced &amp;#39;witty&amp;#39;) is a C++ library to create highly interactive&#xA;web applications,&#xA;with an API that resembles  desktop widget libraries. Internally, Wt&#xA;uses new browser technologies (JavaScript, DOM, AJAX) if available,&#xA;features a dynamic C++-to-JavaScript translation, and reverts to plain&#xA;HTML if necessary.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1491">Wim Dumon</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="../../slides/lightningtalks/Wt.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="154">
      <start>17:45</start>
      <duration>01:15</duration>
      <room>H.1309</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Mozilla BOF</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Mozilla</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;re having an open discussion on Mozilla related topics.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This open discussion is a traditional Birds of a Feather for member of the Mozilla community and people merely interested. This informal discussion will either end when we&amp;#39;re running out of topics or when the room closes.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1541">Axel Hecht</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="155">
      <start>14:45</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>H.1309</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Mozilla Corporation update</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Mozilla</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mike will give an update on the activities of the Mozilla Corporation in the last year and outline the current plannings.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description></description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1551">Mike Schroepfer</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="156">
      <start>15:30</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>H.1309</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>European Mozilla Communities</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Mozilla</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Summary of the situation of European Mozilla local communities.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Analyze of the current situation with Mozilla local communities, general trends, current main issues, last year big sparks, and plans for 2007.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mozilla project has at least local 40 communities all around the world. Those communities are in very different stadiums starting from just-born projects, to huge and stable projects. They vary in almost every single aspect, while they still share a lot of the concept and they follow one of a few career paths. The concept of the talk is to give a summarize of what&amp;#39;s going on out there, how does it work, what are the most interesting things about the local communities, what is the generic trend, where they all are heading, what are the biggest problems, what are the biggest wins, and what the next year will bring!&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1561">Zbigniew Braniecki</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="160">
      <start>17:00</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>H.1309</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>The Mozilla Manifesto</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Mozilla</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An opportunity for people to comment on and propose changes to the draft Mozilla manifesto.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Mozilla project recently published a draft of the &amp;#34;Mozilla Manifesto&amp;#34;, a statement of principles about the way we think the Internet should operate. Comments and discussion on the draft are welcomed, and this talk is an opportunity to do just that.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1601">Gervase Markham</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="161">
      <start>14:00</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>H.1309</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Opening</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Mozilla</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the Mozilla developer room&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description></description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1611">Axel Hecht</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="164">
      <start>16:15</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>H.1309</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>SeaMonkey - Reviving the Suite</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Mozilla</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Current and future developments in the SeaMonkey suite project&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The SeaMonkey internet application suite is the successor of the Mozilla suite, which itself based on the open-sourced code of Netscape&amp;#39;s Communicator product.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The talk will focus on where the SeaMonkey project is right now, almost two years after taking over development of the code and one year after the first SeaMonkey-branded release - and what plans there are for the needed big rework in the immediate future.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1641">Robert Kaiser</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="166">
      <start>11:00</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>Janson</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Keynote: OLPC</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Opening/Closing talks</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Opening keynote about the &lt;a href=&#34;http://laptop.org/&#34;&gt;One Laptop Per Child&lt;/a&gt; project.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introducing the children&amp;#39;s laptop from One Laptop per Child—a potent learning tool created expressly for the world&amp;#39;s poorest children living in its most remote environments.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The laptop was designed collaboratively by experts from both academia and industry, bringing to bear both extraordinary talent and many decades of collective field experience in every aspect of this non-profit humanitarian project. The result is a unique harmony of form and function; a flexible, ultra low-cost, power-efficient, responsive, and durable machine with which nations of the emerging world can leapfrog decades of development—immediately transforming the content and quality of their children&amp;#39;s learning.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The mission of this non-profit association is to develop a low-cost laptop—the &amp;#34;$100 Laptop&amp;#34;—a technology that could revolutionize how we educate the world&amp;#39;s children. Our goal is to provide children around the world with new opportunities to explore, experiment, and express themselves.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Why do children in developing nations need laptops? Laptops are both a window and a tool: a window into the world and a tool with which to think. They are a wonderful way for all children to learn learning through independent interaction and exploration.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1661">Jim Gettys</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://video.fosdem.org/2007/FOSDEM2007-OLPC.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="168">
      <start>14:45</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>H.1308</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Looking ahead to openSUSE 10.3</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>openSUSE</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;openSUSE 10.3 will be the next &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.opensuse.org/&#34;&gt;openSUSE&lt;/a&gt; distribution release.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We like to discuss what major features will be in it and how to deliver a stable with lots of new software.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1681">Andreas Jaeger</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://files.opensuse.org/opensuse/en/1/17/FOSDEM-10.3-talk.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
          <link href="http://ftp5.gwdg.de/pub/opensuse/FOSDEM/2007/fosdem2007-02_Looking_Ahead_to_openSUSE_10.3-1200.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
          <link href="http://ftp5.gwdg.de/pub/opensuse/FOSDEM/2007/fosdem2007-02_Looking_Ahead_to_openSUSE_10.3-320.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora/Low quality)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="169">
      <start>18:00</start>
      <duration>00:30</duration>
      <room>H.1308</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Build Kernel packages with the OBS</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>openSUSE</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The talk shows how to build Kernel packages in the openSUSE build service.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description></description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1691">Jan Blunck</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://ftp5.gwdg.de/pub/opensuse/FOSDEM/2007/fosdem2007-07_Building_Kernel_packages_with_the_OBS-1200.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
          <link href="http://ftp5.gwdg.de/pub/opensuse/FOSDEM/2007/fosdem2007-07_Building_Kernel_packages_with_the_OBS-320.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora/Low quality)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="170">
      <start>16:30</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>H.1308</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>The build service backend</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>openSUSE</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The gory details of the openSUSE build service backend.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The talk goes more into the details of the openSUSE build service backend and shows the possibilities of it&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1701">Michael Schröder</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://ftp5.gwdg.de/pub/opensuse/FOSDEM/2007/fosdem2007-05_The_build_service_backend-1200.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
          <link href="http://ftp5.gwdg.de/pub/opensuse/FOSDEM/2007/fosdem2007-05_The_build_service_backend-320.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora/Low quality)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="171">
      <start>15:30</start>
      <duration>00:15</duration>
      <room>H.1308</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>openSUSE Build Service Overview</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>openSUSE</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction into the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.opensuse.org/Build_Service&#34;&gt;openSUSE Build Service&lt;/a&gt;, why it was created, what are the goals it wants to achieve and a brief overview about its components.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description></description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1711">Adrian Schroeter</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://ftp5.gwdg.de/pub/opensuse/FOSDEM/2007/fosdem2007-03_openSUSE_Build_Service_Overview-1200.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
          <link href="http://ftp5.gwdg.de/pub/opensuse/FOSDEM/2007/fosdem2007-03_openSUSE_Build_Service_Overview-320.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora/Low quality)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="178">
      <start>15:45</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>H.1308</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Packaging made easy</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>openSUSE</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How the openSUSE build service makes building packages easy for developers who don&amp;#39;t care about packaging.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The openSUSE build service is a powerful tool to build installable packages of free software on a Novell hosted build farm. Packages can be built for the openSUSE and various other distributions, including for example Fedora and Ubuntu. Traditionally building packages involves pretty low-level tasks like manually creating tarballs, write detailed control files for the package building tools etc. The openSUSE build service provides more convenient interfaces which don&amp;#39;t require the developer to get too deep into the gory details of packaging software.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This presentation will give an overview and demonstrate some of the tools of the openSUSE build service which make creating installable packages of free software for various distributions easy. It will show how to control the build with the web client, how to interface the build service with upstream source code repositories and what other tools exist to ease the job of packaging software.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1781">Cornelius Schumacher</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://files.opensuse.org/opensuse/en/5/57/FOSDEM_2007_packaging.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
          <link href="http://ftp5.gwdg.de/pub/opensuse/FOSDEM/2007/fosdem2007-04_Packaging_made_easy-1200.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
          <link href="http://ftp5.gwdg.de/pub/opensuse/FOSDEM/2007/fosdem2007-04_Packaging_made_easy-320.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora/Low quality)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="179">
      <start>17:15</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>H.1308</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Participating in creating the openSUSE distribution</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>openSUSE</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The talk will present the way how the openSUSE distribution will get opened for contributions. What requirements need to be fulfilled by the software and the packager.&#xA;The talk makes also a proposal about the used rules to identify software to become part of openSUSE Factory distribution.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As of now the openSUSE distribution gets build in the internal AutoBuild system of SUSE. We will talk about how we think the distribution should get &#xA;created in future using the openSUSE build service.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our goal is to make it transparent how we work and to make it easy to add all kind of contributions (from a small spelling fix up to complete new software) to the openSUSE distribution.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We want to create a platform where all kind contributors can work on the openSUSE distribution. Starting with developers working on SLE products, general openSUSE maintainers and also direct participation of open source projects.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We will show what does influence us, which resources we have and we will make a suggestion how we can decide which software will become part of the openSUSE Factory pool.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1791">Adrian Schroeter</person>
          <person id="1792">Hendrik Vogelsang</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://ftp5.gwdg.de/pub/opensuse/FOSDEM/2007/fosdem2007-06_Participating_in_creating_the_openSUSE_distribution-1200.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
          <link href="http://ftp5.gwdg.de/pub/opensuse/FOSDEM/2007/fosdem2007-06_Participating_in_creating_the_openSUSE_distribution-320.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora/Low quality)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="180">
      <start>14:15</start>
      <duration>00:30</duration>
      <room>H.1308</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>The openSUSE project</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>openSUSE</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The talk gives an overview about the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.opensuse.org/&#34;&gt;openSUSE project&lt;/a&gt; and looking back to what was accomplished the last months.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Why did Novell start the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.opensuse.org/&#34;&gt;openSUSE project&lt;/a&gt; ?&#xA;What is different from other projects?&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Get a short overview of our motivations and plans for the future of the openSUSE project as well as tell us your opinions and discuss with us where openSUSE can go in the future. After last year talk on the FOSDEM we will take the opportunity to look back what was accomplished.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1801">Martin Lasarsch</person>
          <person id="1802">Michael Löffler</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://files.opensuse.org/opensuse/en/3/39/OpenSUSE-Project_FOSDEM2007.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
          <link href="http://ftp5.gwdg.de/pub/opensuse/FOSDEM/2007/fosdem2007-01_The_openSUSE_project-1200.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
          <link href="http://ftp5.gwdg.de/pub/opensuse/FOSDEM/2007/fosdem2007-01_The_openSUSE_project-320.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora/Low quality)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="182">
      <start>18:30</start>
      <duration>00:30</duration>
      <room>H.1308</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Testing the openSUSE distribution</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>openSUSE</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Testing of openSUSE from an internal perspective and how the community can engage.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All interim openSUSE builds are tested by the SUSE QA Team. Of course the publicly released versions of openSUSE get a deeper look.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is an introduction to the testing that is done by SUSE and tools used. We&amp;#39;d like to discuss as well ideas how the openSUSE community can&#xA;engage better in this process.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1821">Holger Sickenberg</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://files.opensuse.org/opensuse/en/f/f6/FOSDEM2007TestingTheOpenSuseDistribution.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
          <link href="http://ftp5.gwdg.de/pub/opensuse/FOSDEM/2007/fosdem2007-08_Testing_the_openSUSE_distribution-1200.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
          <link href="http://ftp5.gwdg.de/pub/opensuse/FOSDEM/2007/fosdem2007-08_Testing_the_openSUSE_distribution-320.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora/Low quality)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="187">
      <start>17:30</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.117</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Django</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Python</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.djangoproject.com/&#34;&gt;Django&lt;/a&gt; is a high-level Python Web framework that encourages rapid development and clean, pragmatic design.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The talk will cover:&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; an overview of the Django web framework&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; a small sample application to illustrate how quickly you can solve a real world problem in Django while still having a clean and maintainable code base&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; how Dojo can be integrated with Djanjo to give your application some Ajax coolness&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; pointers to get you started with Django in no time&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1871">Pim Van Heuven</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="188">
      <start>16:30</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.117</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>How to lay an egg</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Python</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This presentation introduces how to package and advertise an open source python projects with distutils and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://peak.telecommunity.com/DevCenter/setuptools&#34;&gt;setuptools extension&lt;/a&gt;.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; what is a python egg (basically the python equivalent of a java .jar file)&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; how to install existing eggs with easy_install&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; how to build a standard distutils python package&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; how to build python eggs and publish them on the cheeseshop&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1881">Olivier Grisel</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="194">
      <start>14:30</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.117</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Test and Documentation Driven Development</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Python</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Test Driven Development using &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.python.org/lib/module-unittest.html&#34;&gt;unittest&lt;/a&gt; and Documentation Driven Development using &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.python.org/lib/module-doctest.html&#34;&gt;doctest&lt;/a&gt;.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first part of the presentation introduces Test Driven Development in Python with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.python.org/lib/module-unittest.html&#34;&gt;unittest module&lt;/a&gt;. TDD is a common eXtreme Programming strategy to dramatically enhanced the QA of a Python project.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The second part of the presentation focuses on the Python specific &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.python.org/lib/module-doctest.html&#34;&gt;doctest module&lt;/a&gt; that allows pushing TDD to the next level: Documentation Driven Development.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We will show how to write runnable documentation that is used at all stages of the life of a python project:&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; technical specifications drafting of new features&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; testing ongoing implementation&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; introducing living examples to new developers&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; ensuring the documentation stays up-to-date when refactoring&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1941">Olivier Grisel</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="195">
      <start>15:30</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.117</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Tux Droid, a Python-Fueled robot</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Python</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Presentation of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tux-is-alive.com/&#34;&gt;Tux Droid&lt;/a&gt;, a small wireless robot controlled from a computer through a Python API.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tux Droid is a tux-shaped robot wirelessly controlled from a computer running Linux. It can talk and move, but also listen and react to events.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The wireless link provides full-duplex audio, commands and status transfer. It is then possible to stream music and sounds to and from Tux Droid while blinking the eyes and waving the flippers, and detecting if the head button is pressed. Tux Droid’s embedded processing is only meant to interface sensors and actuators. We will show you how, by developing a complete python API, we can leverage the embedded basic set of features to get a complex robot which can bring life to your applications and act as a desktop companion.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The wireless link is the key here, it provides Tux Droid with access to all the power of Python. Python’s interpreter is of great help if you don’t have any clue about programming languages but would like to make your first steps into robotics. Simple scripts to control your robot are really at your fingertips. But we could of course get much more out of Python and Tux Droid.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1951">David Bourgeois</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="198">
      <start>14:00</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>Janson</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>ReactOS</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Kernel</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ReactOS is an advanced free open source operating system providing a ground-up implementation of a Microsoft Windows® XP compatible operating system.&#xA;ReactOS aims to achieve complete binary compatibility with both applications and device drivers meant for NT and XP operating systems, by using a similar architecture and providing a complete and equivalent public interface.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Topics of Aleksey&amp;#39;s talk:&#xA;1. Introduction, what is ReactOS.&#xA;2. Goals of implementing ReactOS.&#xA;3. &amp;#34;ReactOS is not Unix!&amp;#34; - the kernel, HAL, bootloader and drivers. Overall architecture.&#xA;4. Compatibility from technical point of view. How close to go / playing a catch-up game.&#xA;5. Current ReactOS in action - screenshots / live demo (if possible).&#xA;6. Questions.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1981">Aleksey Bragin</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://video.fosdem.org/2007/FOSDEM2007-ReactOS.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="199">
      <start>16:00</start>
      <duration>02:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.120</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Research and Libre Software (I)</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Research Room</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Presentation of reviewed short papers.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; AdaCore Quality Procedures: Romain Berrendonner, Jose Ruiz&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; Linux distribution testing and quality assurance: current developments of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edos-project.org/&#34;&gt;EDOS project&lt;/a&gt; and open questions: Francois Dechelle&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; A reference model for F/OSS process management: Ciaran Bryce&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; Use of grid computing for Debian Quality Assurance: Lucas Nussbaum&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1991">Ciaran Bryce</person>
          <person id="1992">Francois Déchelle</person>
          <person id="1993">Romain Berrendonner</person>
          <person id="1994">Lucas Nussbaum</person>
          <person id="1995">Jose Ruiz</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://gsyc.escet.urjc.es/~herraiz/fosdem2007/papers/AdaCore_QA.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
          <link href="http://gsyc.escet.urjc.es/~herraiz/fosdem2007/slides/edos-wp3-fosdem-research-workshop-presentation.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
          <link href="http://gsyc.escet.urjc.es/~herraiz/fosdem2007/papers/edos-wp3-fosdem-research-workshop.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
          <link href="http://gsyc.escet.urjc.es/~herraiz/fosdem2007/papers/pawlakbryce.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
          <link href="http://gsyc.escet.urjc.es/~herraiz/fosdem2007/slides/gridqa.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
          <link href="http://gsyc.escet.urjc.es/~herraiz/fosdem2007/papers/grid-qa.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
          <link href="http://libresoft.urjc.es/videos/FOSDEM07/20070224_AdaCore_Berrendonner-Ruiz.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="201">
      <start>14:30</start>
      <duration>01:30</duration>
      <room>AW1.120</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Research about libre software in Europe</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Research Room</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Presentation of research projects -- comments, questions and discussion session.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flossworld.org/&#34;&gt;FLOSSWORLD&lt;/a&gt;: Rishab Ghosh&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sqo-oss.eu/&#34;&gt;SQO-OSS&lt;/a&gt;: Georgios Gousios&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flossmetrics.org/&#34;&gt;FLOSSMETRICS&lt;/a&gt;: Jesus M. Gonzalez-Barahona&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.qualoss.org/&#34;&gt;QUALOSS&lt;/a&gt;: Jean-Christophe Deprez&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="2011">Jean-Christophe Deprez</person>
          <person id="2012">Jesus M. Gonzalez Barahona</person>
          <person id="2013">Georgios Gousios</person>
          <person id="2014">Rishab Ghosh</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://gsyc.escet.urjc.es/~herraiz/fosdem2007/slides/flossworld-intro4.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
          <link href="http://gsyc.escet.urjc.es/~herraiz/fosdem2007/slides/SQO-OSS_P_FOSDEM_.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
          <link href="http://gsyc.escet.urjc.es/~herraiz/fosdem2007/slides/flossmetrics.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
          <link href="http://gsyc.escet.urjc.es/~herraiz/fosdem2007/slides/QUALOSS_FOSDEM_20070224.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
          <link href="http://gsyc.escet.urjc.es/~herraiz/fosdem2007/slides/Qualipso-presentation.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="203">
      <start>14:15</start>
      <duration>00:15</duration>
      <room>AW1.120</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Research Room</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome, schedule and practical issues.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description></description>
      <persons>
          <person id="2031">Jesus M. Gonzalez Barahona</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="206">
      <start>10:30</start>
      <duration>00:30</duration>
      <room>Janson</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Status of Software Patents in Europe</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Opening/Closing talks</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Status update on software patents in Europe, by the president of the FFII.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pieter Hintjens, the current president of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ffii.org/&#34;&gt;FFII&lt;/a&gt; will give us an update on the current state of things regarding &lt;a href=&#34;http://swpats.ffii.org/&#34;&gt;software patents in Europe&lt;/a&gt;.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The fight is not over, and the FFII is still hard at work.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="2061">Pieter Hintjens</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://video.fosdem.org/2007/FOSDEM2007-Status-of-Software-Patents-in-Europe.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="207">
      <start>12:00</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>Janson</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Keynote: Liberating Java</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Opening/Closing talks</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Liberating Java&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sun Microsystems committed to liberate all its Java implementations under the GPL.&#xA;What does this mean for the Free software community ?&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Simon will be talking about Java and Free Software, as well as the issues around them and Sun&amp;#39;s vision on Free Software in both the community and in the commercial world.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He will also give an overview of the projects some key people at Sun have been leading and contributing to in the community.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="2071">Simon Phipps</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://video.fosdem.org/2007/FOSDEM2007-Liberating-Java.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="208">
      <start>10:00</start>
      <duration>00:30</duration>
      <room>Janson</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Opening/Closing talks</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;FOSDEM Opening Talk&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The FOSDEM Opening Talk, including the famous FOSDEM dance.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="2081">FOSDEM</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://video.fosdem.org/2007/FOSDEM2007-Welcome.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="209">
      <start>14:00</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>Chavanne</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>X.org</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Desktop Applications</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;X.org: Projects and People&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This talk presents an overview of the current projects related to the X window system and some of the people involved in them.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The goals and challenges facing each project will be presented along with a brief history of a couple of the contributors. Rather than simply presenting where X.org is today, the hope is that this presentation will encourage people to watch X grow and come help us solve issues facing the free software desktop.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="2091">Keith Packard</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://video.fosdem.org/2007/FOSDEM2007-Xorg.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="210">
      <start>14:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.121</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>A build environment for X</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>X.org</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A modular build environment for X.org&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The monolithic X tree forced the user to build all X server and client side pieces at once even when only a small subset of the entire suite was needed.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The modular environment now allows to build any piece separately provided that the prerequisites are installed.&#xA;This caused us to loose the &amp;#39;big picture&amp;#39; ie. it made it hard to determine what these dependencies are and to grab and build these.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We present an environment that allows us to retrieve these dependencies automatically. Furthermore it allows one to download and build all dependencies. It does not require any additional tools installed on the system beyond what is already required for building the tree.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="2101">Egbert Eich</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="211">
      <start>18:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.121</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Let&#39;s finish COMPOSITE</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>X.org</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Brainstorming/hacking session where we try to get an overview of what we need to do to finish COMPOSITE.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;E.g. how to implement redirected Xv and OpenGL, how to hook up damage for AIGLX, what about input redirection, etc.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="2111">Kristian Høgsberg</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="212">
      <start>15:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.121</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>GGI/KGI</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>X.org</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;GGI/KGI as a model for an improved graphics driver architecture&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With the current graphics architecture on GNU/Linux (and similar systems), responsibilities aren&amp;#39;t clearly regulated: Between kernel (text console or&#xA;framebuffer), X drivers, DRM, DirectFB, SVGATextMode, and some other hacks, there is a lot of friction -- non-working suspend/resume, lost or distorted display on console switch, unusable console after X server of console application crashes etc. are the result.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Incompatibilities and configuration problems are ubiquitous. Clearly, a better integrated approach is desirable.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This talk discusses the problems with the current architecture, and presents GGI/KGI as a model for a more unified and robust design.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="2121">Olaf Buddenhagen</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="213">
      <start>17:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.121</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>X.org myths</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>X.org</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;X.org myths/Open Q&amp;amp;A session&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;X is slow. X uses up all the system memory. X is bloated.&#xA;In this talk, I&amp;#39;ll discuss common X.org misconceptions and try to debunk them.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Everyone is also welcome to come by and ask questions here, and have X.org hackers answer.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="2131">Stéphane Marchesin</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="219">
      <start>16:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.121</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Xenocara: X.Org modular for OpenBSD</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>X.org</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Xenocara: adapting X.Org modular to OpenBSD&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After a few short reminders on OpenBSD, this talk will show how the modular X.Org build system affected the integration of X in OpenBSD and the solutions that have been implemented. I&amp;#39;ll will also present some ideas about general portability and interoperability concerns in the context of non Linux platforms for future X developments.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="2191">Matthieu Herrb</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  </day>
  <day index="2" date="2007-02-26">
  <event id="1">
      <start>12:00</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>Janson</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Bacula</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Security</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bacula.org/&#34;&gt;Bacula&lt;/a&gt; is a Free/Open Source enterprise quality network backup solution.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kern will give an overview of each of the six &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bacula.org/&#34;&gt;Bacula&lt;/a&gt; components, how they all work together, and highlights of the functionality offered.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He will present a few example configuration files then terminate the presentation with a demo of a simple backup and restore followed by a brief look at a web based management tool that presents an overall view of all your backups.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="11">Kern Sibbald</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="../../slides/maintracks/bacula.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
          <link href="http://video.fosdem.org/2007/FOSDEM2007-Bacula.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="2">
      <start>17:15</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>Janson</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Beyond GPLv3</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Opening/Closing talks</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Beyond GPLv3: Free Software today and tomorrow&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After 2006 already saw massive changes in the Free Software ecosystem, this year is promising to become the most exciting year for Free Software yet.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Major industrial players update their strategies, and the GNU General Public License (GPL) has become a mainstream license to consider for most enterprises. With the upcoming release of the GNU General Public License, and the various ongoing battles between the European Commission and Microsoft, as well as the issues of ODF vs OpenXML, the world is changing fast.&#xA;All of these are signs of increasing maturity in the Free Software ecosystem.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In his keynote, Georg Greve will give an overview of the situation, speak briefly about the GPLv3 and its relevance to Free Software, and explain how the Freedom Task Force and other initiatives fit into the larger picture of an exciting 2007.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="21">Georg Greve</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="../../slides/maintracks/beyond_gpl3.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
          <link href="http://video.fosdem.org/2007/FOSDEM2007-BeyondGPLv3.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="3">
      <start>12:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>Ferrer</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>CAcert Signing</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Key Signing</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CAcert signing session.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;http://fosdem.org/2007/keysigning#cacert&#34;&gt;http://fosdem.org/2007/keysigning#cacert&lt;/a&gt; for details.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="31">Johan Braeken</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="4">
      <start>16:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>H.2214</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Contributing to CentOS</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>CentOS + Fedora</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With an ever increasing number of installations, more and more people from the community want to get involved with the project in either a personal role or as an organisation helping out. My talk will focus on how such people can join the CentOS effort and what kind of areas we need the most help with.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description></description>
      <persons>
          <person id="41">Karanbir Singh</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="7">
      <start>10:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>H.2214</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Introduction to CentOS + Q&amp;A</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>CentOS + Fedora</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What is CentOS? Where did it come from? Who is responsible for it? And who needs an enterprise distribution anyhow?&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CentOS is an enterprise class linux distribution with a strong, fast growing active community behind it. This talk will give an overview of the distribution and the people behind it. After a short &amp;#34;historical&amp;#34; overview this talk will center on the available CentOS versions, and give an overview of what is in the distribution. This talk is also trying to explain in which fields an enterprise class distribution might be useful for the user or the administrator. Showing the places where the community is doing work at the moment and a brief introduction of the technical aspects behind CentOS will top off this talk.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="71">Ralph Angenendt</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="9">
      <start>14:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>H.2214</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>CentOS infrastructure and roadmap</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>CentOS + Fedora</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Presentation of CentOS infrastructure and roadmap.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CentOS has 30 servers, 150 mirrors, millions of users.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This talk will describe how to manage the infrastructure and also what the plans are for the future of the CentOS project.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="91">Lance Davis</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://wiki.centos.org/Events/Fosdem2007?action=AttachFile&amp;do=get&amp;target=Lance-fosdem.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="10">
      <start>12:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>H.2214</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>RPM Packaging</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>CentOS + Fedora</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Increasingly, managing collections of package metadata is more important than building packages. This presentation proposes several possible implementations in RPM development that may simplify creating collections.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Several RPM development topics will be discussed: &#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; using easily extracted XML or YAML markup to represent metadata in *.rpm packages. &#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; generating Provides: dependencies during install, not during build. &#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; adding user-definable extensible tags to rpm metadata. &#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; automating package scriptlet actions through rule based triggers.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="101">Jeff Johnson</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="12">
      <start>09:15</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>H.1302</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Metisse: this is not a 3D desktop!</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>CrossDesktop</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Metisse is an X-based window system designed with two goals in mind.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First, it should make it easy for HCI researchers to design and implement innovative window management techniques Second, it should conform to existing standards and be robust and efficient enough to be used on a daily basis, making it a suitable platform for the evaluation of the proposed techniques.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="121">Frédéric Crozat</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="13">
      <start>10:00</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>H.1302</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Strigi internals</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>CrossDesktop</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Strigi, the fastest and smallest desktop search engine, combines stream-based content analysis with an abstract index interface. Revolutionary tools like deepfind, deepgrep, the Strigi daemon and a universal metadata extractor for the free desktop are the result.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Strigi introduces a new way of looking at metadata and file formats that enables the creation of very efficient tools for improving the way users handle their data. It does so by using simple C++ code with very few dependencies.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Two concepts are central: stream-based data analysis and an abstract index interface. The former provides a standardized way of looking at metadata and embedded files. It allows reading arbitrarily deeply nested files with very low cpu and memory consumption. Embedded files of all types are handled in the same way, no matter if they are email attachments, zip file entries, files in an rpm or deb file or pictures embedded in a pdf file. This interface allows for applications like deepfind and deepgrep, versions of &amp;#39;find&amp;#39; and &amp;#39;grep&amp;#39; that also list arbitrary deeply nested files.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The latter, the common interface for indexes, is also essential for deepfind and deepgrep, but in addition, it enables a universal metadata extractor which can hugely speed up the indexing phase of any desktop search engine. On top of that, it lets the Strigi desktop search daemon be ignorant about its storage backend.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This presentation explains the technology that allows Strigi to be as fast as it is and will show how other projects can benefit too by using the programs and libraries provided by Strigi.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="131">Jos van den Oever</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://www.kde.org/kdeslides/fosdem2007/2007-02-vandenoever-strigi_internals.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
          <link href="http://www.kde.org/kdeslides/fosdem2007/2007-02-vandenoever-strigi_internals.odp">Slides (OOo)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="14">
      <start>11:30</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>H.1302</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Telepathy</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>CrossDesktop</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://telepathy.freedesktop.org/&#34;&gt;Telepathy project&lt;/a&gt; aims to make real time communications, such as instant messaging and voice/video calls, a better experience for both developers and users. It makes it easy to build protocol-agnostic clients and allows code to be reused between desktops.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This talk will cover what we in the project have done up to now, and also future directions for Telepathy.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="141">Dafydd Harries</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="15">
      <start>10:45</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>H.1302</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Wasabi</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>CrossDesktop</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.freedesktop.org/wiki/WasabiAbout&#34;&gt;Wasabi&lt;/a&gt; - Unified Desktop Search- and Metadata Specification&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.freedesktop.org/wiki/WasabiAbout&#34;&gt;Wasabi&lt;/a&gt; is an umbrella project with the purpose of providing unified APIs and specs for desktop search- and metadata services.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this talk Mikkel will outline the ideas behind the Wasabi project, its&amp;#39; past, present, and future, and will present the current proposal for a search spec and API, which should be in a public evaluation period during FOSDEM 2007.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="151">Mikkel Kamstrup</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="17">
      <start>16:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.125</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Automating installations</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Debian</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Automating installations using preseeding in Debian Installer&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An introduction to how installing Debian can be automated using &amp;#34;preseeding&amp;#34;.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The talk will give some background information on how preseeding is basically just making use of the debconf protocol, which preseeding methods are available, and how to create a preconfiguration file. Some potential problems and current limitations of using preseeding will be discussed as well.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="171">Frans Pop</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://meetings-archive.debian.net/pub/debian-meetings/2007/fosdem/ogg_theora/720x576/Automating_installations-Frans_Pop.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
          <link href="http://meetings-archive.debian.net/pub/debian-meetings/2007/fosdem/xvid/Automating_installations-Frans_Pop_xvid.avi">Video (DIVX)</link>
          <link href="http://meetings-archive.debian.net/pub/debian-meetings/2007/fosdem/ogg_theora/360x288/Automating_installations-Frans_Pop.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora/Low quality)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="18">
      <start>17:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.125</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Debian-Community.org (pre)launch</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Debian</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This talk will explain what &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.debian-community.org/&#34;&gt;www.debian-community.org&lt;/a&gt; tries to achieve, why and how, also looking for feedback and actual participation in this project!&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Join the party!&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.debian-community.org/&#34;&gt;debian-community.org&lt;/a&gt; is an effort to give back to the community that has a great share in making debian the universal OS that it is. Many people contribute to Debian: obviously the developers and package maintainers, but also translators and artists and everybody who files bugs or helps someone else on a mailing list. If you want to be part of the debian-community, but dont want to become a developer or maintainer, Debian didn&amp;#39;t, so far, offer you much in reward.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So this (still somewhat whacky :) idea was born, to offer a nice email-address to anybody who wants one (and did at least a little for debian) and to setup planet(s), which will aggregate more than just the developers and wannabe-developers. And, of course, we want to promote (&amp;#34;sell&amp;#34;) t-shirts, because everybody loves t-shirts and they are an excellent way to show about what you care!&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Other ideas how to improve the community, so that more people have fun contributing to the universal OS, are very welcome!&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="181">Holger Levsen</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://meetings-archive.debian.net/pub/debian-meetings/2007/fosdem/slides/Debian-Community.org_pre-launch-Holger_Levsen/20070225-debian-community.org-prelaunch.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
          <link href="http://meetings-archive.debian.net/pub/debian-meetings/2007/fosdem/slides/Debian-Community.org_pre-launch-Holger_Levsen/20070225-debian-community.org-prelaunch.odp">Slides (OOo)</link>
          <link href="http://meetings-archive.debian.net/pub/debian-meetings/2007/fosdem/ogg_theora/720x576/Debian-Community.org_pre-launch-Holger_Levsen.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
          <link href="http://meetings-archive.debian.net/pub/debian-meetings/2007/fosdem/xvid/Debian-Community.org_pre-launch-Holger_Levsen_xvid.avi">Video (DIVX)</link>
          <link href="http://meetings-archive.debian.net/pub/debian-meetings/2007/fosdem/ogg_theora/360x288/Debian-Community.org_pre-launch-Holger_Levsen.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora/Low quality)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="20">
      <start>09:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.125</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Formal Dependency Management</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Debian</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Formal Dependency Management in Debian Package Repositories&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this talk we will briefly sketch the research that has been done concerning the maintenance of large package-based distributions and the formal management of inter-package dependencies, in the context of the EDOS Project.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The toolset that has been developed starting from this research will be showcased in its Debian incarnation:&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; edos-debcheck: a dependency checker for finding inconsistencies in Debian repositories.&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; edos-history: a package repository exploration tool that is able to handle historical Debian repositories data.&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; anla: a web service that reports the analysis of Debian repositories over time.&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; tart: a distribution &amp;#34;thinner&amp;#34; used to build custom Debian distributions.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="201">Berke Durak</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://meetings-archive.debian.net/pub/debian-meetings/2007/fosdem/slides/Formal_Dependency_Management-Berke_Durak/Formal_Dependency_Management-Berke_Durak.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
          <link href="http://meetings-archive.debian.net/pub/debian-meetings/2007/fosdem/ogg_theora/720x576/Formal_Dependency_Management-Berke_Durak.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
          <link href="http://meetings-archive.debian.net/pub/debian-meetings/2007/fosdem/xvid/Formal_Dependency_Management-Berke_Durak_xvid.avi">Video (DIVX)</link>
          <link href="http://meetings-archive.debian.net/pub/debian-meetings/2007/fosdem/ogg_theora/360x288/Formal_Dependency_Management-Berke_Durak.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora/Low quality)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="21">
      <start>11:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.125</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Secret debian internals</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Debian</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Debian is full of nice undocumented pieces of infrastructure: you can access control files of all source packages, aggregated package lists, popcon results, raw BTS data, Debtags categories, maintainer/comaintainer databases, build logs and much more.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since it&amp;#39;s usually hard to find documentation on what is available and on how to use it, I&amp;#39;ll show you what I know. People from the audience can show some more. Hopefully someone will blog a summary on Planet Debian.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then we hack.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="211">Enrico Zini</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://meetings-archive.debian.net/pub/debian-meetings/2007/fosdem/slides/Secret_debian_internals-Enrico_Zini/Secret_debian_internals-Enrico_Zini.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
          <link href="http://meetings-archive.debian.net/pub/debian-meetings/2007/fosdem/ogg_theora/720x576/Secret_debian_internals-Enrico_Zini.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
          <link href="http://meetings-archive.debian.net/pub/debian-meetings/2007/fosdem/xvid/Secret_debian_internals-Enrico_Zini_xvid.avi">Video (DIVX)</link>
          <link href="http://meetings-archive.debian.net/pub/debian-meetings/2007/fosdem/ogg_theora/360x288/Secret_debian_internals-Enrico_Zini.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora/Low quality)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="22">
      <start>13:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.125</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Kernel and d-i in lenny and beyond</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Debian</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A reflection on the kernel, and its relationship with d-i in lenny and beyond&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The title says it all, but the talk will mention issues regarding the kernel, what we have achieved since the kernel team took over, what we failed to achieve for etch, plans regarding the non-free firmware issue, the non-free firmware .udeb archive, and ideas on how the new initramfs ramdisk format may be taken to profit to improve the way d-i is built and works.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="221">Sven Luther</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://meetings-archive.debian.net/pub/debian-meetings/2007/fosdem/ogg_theora/720x576/Kernel_and_d-i_in_lenny_and_beyond-Sven_Luther.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
          <link href="http://meetings-archive.debian.net/pub/debian-meetings/2007/fosdem/xvid/Kernel_and_d-i_in_lenny_and_beyond-Sven_Luther_xvid.avi">Video (DIVX)</link>
          <link href="http://meetings-archive.debian.net/pub/debian-meetings/2007/fosdem/ogg_theora/360x288/Kernel_and_d-i_in_lenny_and_beyond-Sven_Luther.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora/Low quality)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="24">
      <start>14:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.125</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Running Debian on Inexpensive Network Storage Devices</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Debian</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Network Storage Devices (NAS) are gaining popularity and are available quite inexpensively. For most customers, they are basically just a hard drive that you connect to the network for file storage.&#xA;In reality, these devices are complete, even if fairly low-end, computers - and Debian can be installed on some of them.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This talk will show how combining a NAS with Debian gives you a low-power and quiet server for home use.&#xA;In particular, it will cover two devices: the Linksys NSLU2 and the Thecus N2100.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="241">Martin Michlmayr</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://meetings-archive.debian.net/pub/debian-meetings/2007/fosdem/slides/Running_Debian_on_Inexpensive_Network_Storage_Devices-Martin_Michlmayr/debian-on-nas.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
          <link href="http://meetings-archive.debian.net/pub/debian-meetings/2007/fosdem/ogg_theora/720x576/Running_Debian_on_Inexpensive_Network_Storage_Devices-Martin_Michlmayr.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
          <link href="http://meetings-archive.debian.net/pub/debian-meetings/2007/fosdem/xvid/Running_Debian_on_Inexpensive_Network_Storage_Devices-Martin_Michlmayr_xvid.avi">Video (DIVX)</link>
          <link href="http://meetings-archive.debian.net/pub/debian-meetings/2007/fosdem/ogg_theora/360x288/Running_Debian_on_Inexpensive_Network_Storage_Devices-Martin_Michlmayr.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora/Low quality)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="25">
      <start>10:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.125</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Netconf</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Debian</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Debian&amp;#39;s ifupdown has served us well for many years: it is the established standard, provides flexible hooks and thus allows many other programmes to integrate with it, and handles the most common scenarios. However, with mobile computing, VPN, WLAN and other technology related to networking, more flexibility is needed.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;netconf Martin&amp;#39;s brainchild to address these needs, but it&amp;#39;s still vapourware, which is why this proposal is an invitation to a brainstorming session. I want to start implementing netconf at Debcamp7.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The plan is to provide a backwards-compatible, stateless network configuration system, which is extensible to cater for today&amp;#39;s networking needs. Environment detection, WLAN roaming, automated VPN setup, use of the DHCP option fields for various configuration tasks (think: SMTP smart server, NTP server, etc.) are some of the buzzwords I came up with. Furthermore, control sockets and policy-based access control should make it easy to allow normal users to perform the essential tasks from their desktops.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="251">Martin Krafft</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://meetings-archive.debian.net/pub/debian-meetings/2007/fosdem/ogg_theora/720x576/Netconf-Martin_Krafft.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
          <link href="http://meetings-archive.debian.net/pub/debian-meetings/2007/fosdem/xvid/Netconf-Martin_Krafft_xvid.avi">Video (DIVX)</link>
          <link href="http://meetings-archive.debian.net/pub/debian-meetings/2007/fosdem/ogg_theora/360x288/Netconf-Martin_Krafft.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora/Low quality)</link>
          <link href="http://meetings-archive.debian.net/pub/debian-meetings/2007/fosdem/slides/Netconf-Martin_Krafft/slides.s5.html">Slides (HTML)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="26">
      <start>15:00</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>AW1.125</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Let&#39;s port together</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Debian</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#39;s port together. Debian fun&#x9;for everyone&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this talk we will explain how modern system architectures look like and what implications the architecture choices have on the software side of things. Architecture differences like endianess, alignment requirements, cache coherency, out of order execution and representation of standard C types and their impact on portability will be discussed as well as strategies for avoiding or working around these problems.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="261">Peter De Schrijver</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://meetings-archive.debian.net/pub/debian-meetings/2007/fosdem/slides/Lets_port_together-Peter_De_Schrijver/Lets_port_together-Peter_De_Schrijver.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
          <link href="http://meetings-archive.debian.net/pub/debian-meetings/2007/fosdem/ogg_theora/720x576/Lets_port_together-Peter_De_Schrijver.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
          <link href="http://meetings-archive.debian.net/pub/debian-meetings/2007/fosdem/xvid/Lets_port_together-Peter_De_Schrijver_xvid.avi">Video (DIVX)</link>
          <link href="http://meetings-archive.debian.net/pub/debian-meetings/2007/fosdem/ogg_theora/360x288/Lets_port_together-Peter_De_Schrijver.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora/Low quality)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="30">
      <start>11:00</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>Chavanne</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Drupal</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Web</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dries will explain why &lt;a href=&#34;http://drupal.org/&#34;&gt;Drupal&lt;/a&gt; is the answer, regardless of your question.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this presentation, we talk about the state of &lt;a href=&#34;http://drupal.org/&#34;&gt;Drupal&lt;/a&gt;, a modular open source content management system and web application framework.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We let you discover the world of Drupal, and help you figure out why you want to use Drupal (or not).&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="301">Dries Buytaert</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://video.fosdem.org/2007/FOSDEM2007-Drupal.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="32">
      <start>16:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.126</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>eCos RTOS in commercial use</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Embedded</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The eCos RTOS in commercial use - the digital camera back Eyelike eMotion&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Eyelike eMotion is a digital back for medium format cameras, available in variants with a 22 megapixel and a 33 megapixel sensor. In contrast to all other cameras developed by Jenoptik LOS before, it is a mobile camera and is intended to be used indepedent from a computer.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With these requirements a new platform was needed, more powerful than the 16bit microcontroller used exclusively until then.&#xA;Due to the much increased complexity of the required firmware the need for an operating system arose. Some options were evaluated and eCos was selected.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;eCos features employed in this project will be introduced. The development environment both on Linux and Windows as well as the software quality&#xA;assurance means will be presented, organizational issues as well. Finally strong and weak areas of eCos will be discussed and future directions&#xA;are shown.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="321">Alexander Neundorf</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="../../slides/devrooms/embedded/Alexander_Neundorf_ecos_in_commercial_use.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="34">
      <start>14:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.126</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Linux for embedding network devices</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Embedded</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Overview of design and implementation methodology to embed Linux based network devices.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The embedded boards are emerging as the next generation of advanced communication computers.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Linux and standard embedded networking hardware allows technology integrators to produce better solutions.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The objective of this presentation is to give an overview of design and implementation methodology to embed Linux based network devices. The steps are illustrated by embedding a network security product (e.g. VPN) on Soekris net4521 and RouterBOARD 230, to create linux-based Embedded Network Device. &#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Other topics that will be discussed are our experience while porting device drivers among Linux kernel versions and building toolchains to prepare distribution for target embedded platform. It also throws light on the impact of embedded hardware on the performance of linux-based VPN application.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="341">Bhagyashri Katole</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="../../slides/devrooms/embedded/Bhagyashri_Katole_no_show.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="35">
      <start>13:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.126</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Open Hardware Manager</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Embedded</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lunch discussion about: Open Hardware Manager: Device policy on an embedded platform.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The discussion panel will try to guide the discussion and consistes of people who are used to deal with Embedded Linux and/or power management.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The latest phones, set top boxes and Internet tablets are increasingly choosing Linux as the OS of choice. All of these embedded devices require system wide code for hardware policy control. There is currently no standardization of the hardware management interfaces and no upstream development in this area.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Open Hardware Manager is a small open source system policy daemon which sits above HAL and abstracts out common hardware management tasks such as controlling heat dissipation on embedded devices. OHM is product and vendor neutral and is currently being prototyped by a small team of developers including Richard Hughes and Rob Taylor.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The problem space will be discussed, and typical use-cases, followed by a quick discussion on OHM. Initial design ideas, along with scope and future plans will hopefully initiate free discussion.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="351">Discussion Panel</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="36">
      <start>15:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.126</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>OpenEZX</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Embedded</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://openezx.org/&#34;&gt;OpenEZX&lt;/a&gt;, how to free Motorola linux smartphones.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; Hardware overview about Motorola Linux smartphones. Old phones, current phones and perhaps something about future phones. Hardware similarities between and differences between phones.&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; Software overview about the Motorola EZX software.&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; The story to get the GPL code from Motorola.&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; Introduction OpenEZX / History / Goals&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; Bootloader and kernel loading&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; Status of the current hardware support. Kernel driver, tools and stuff.&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; Future plans of OpenEZX. Especially using of the OpenMoko framework&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="361">Stefan Schmidt</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="../../slides/devrooms/embedded/Stefan_Schmidt_OpenEZX.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="39">
      <start>12:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.126</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Open Source Embedded Development with Qtopia</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Embedded</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lorn will explain the development procedure including development of new device support through the use of device configurations using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.trolltech.com/developer/downloads/qtopia/coregpl&#34;&gt;Qtopia 4 Open Source Edition&lt;/a&gt; as well as the Greenphone SDK.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.trolltech.com/products/qtopia&#34;&gt;Qtopia&lt;/a&gt; is at the forefront of the Linux Embedded gui development world.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Qtopia has always been open source, and with the release of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.trolltech.com/developer/downloads/qtopia/coregpl&#34;&gt;Qtopia 4 Open Source Edition&lt;/a&gt;, more source code than every before has been released as Open Source.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.trolltech.com/&#34;&gt;Trolltech&lt;/a&gt; believes in the power of the GPL, which is why we release Qt and Qtopia under a dual license scheme, so the free code always remains free. Other companies say they embrace open source, but really only want to leverage development they don&amp;#39;t have to pay for, and only deliver a partial framework.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now Trolltech has (soon) released Qtopia 4 Open Source Edition, developers can once again develop free software for an up to date Qtopia, which includes Qtopia Phones, such as the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.trolltech.com/products/qtopia/greenphone&#34;&gt;Greenphone&lt;/a&gt;, released at the end of 2006.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Qtopia 4 is even easier to get started than before, as now there is only one package to download, configure and compile.&#xA;Lorn will explain the development procedure including development of new device support through the use of device configurations.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He will also explain the Greenphone SDK, so all developers can develop free applications for Qtopia Phone Edition.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="391">Lorn Potter</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="../../slides/devrooms/embedded/Lorn_Potter_QT.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="41">
      <start>17:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.126</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Linux in embedded security devices</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Embedded</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Linux in embedded security devices: a showcase&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As we all know, GNU/Linux has become a very stable and secure operating system. Companies worldwide are starting to see this and have come to a&#xA;point where linux really is a key differentiator in their product portfolio.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of such product portfolios is the latest product line of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.idcs.be/&#34;&gt;IDCS&lt;/a&gt;, a company specialised in Integrated Security &amp;amp; Video&#xA;Systems. By integrating standard open source products like openssl, apache, postgresql and others, IDCS has build a range of IP-based security&#xA;devices for access control.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This presentation will discuss:&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; system architecture&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; open source components&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; benefits of linux&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; mesh networks using PoE and SSL&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="411">Jan Veldeman</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="../../slides/devrooms/embedded/Jan_Veldeman_embedded_security_devices.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="42">
      <start>10:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.126</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>SH-2A Linux kernel</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Embedded</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Implementation of SH-2(A) Linux kernel&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yoshinori ported linux-2.6 to SH-2 and SH-2A processors of Renesas Technorogy.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SH-3 and SH-4 were supported in the past, but SH-2 needed to be implemented because the architecture was different from those processors.&#xA;Yoshinori will introduce his implementation for SH-2 equivalence mainly on such a part.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="421">Yoshinori Sato</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="../../slides/devrooms/embedded/Yoshinori_Sato_SH2_porting.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="43">
      <start>11:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.126</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>XIP: past, present, future</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Embedded</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;XIP: the past, the present and... the future ?&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;XIP stands for eXecute In Place. This technology allows the code to run directly from where it&amp;#39;s stored 9ie flash) instead of being copied to RAM first. It might be very useful in terms of boot time reduction and RAM usage optimization for Linux-powered embedded devices, especiallylow-end ones.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This talk will give some brief XIP background, cover both Linux kernel XIP and application XIP, its objectives, pros and contras, as well as some measurement results on boot and execution time. Though XIP is currently known to be supported mostly on ARM, this talk will cover XIP implementation on other architectures, such as MIPS.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some custom XIP modifications and areas for further XIP development will also be given.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="431">Vitaly Wool</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="../../slides/devrooms/embedded/Vitaly_Wool_XIP.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="45">
      <start>17:00</start>
      <duration>00:30</duration>
      <room>H.2214</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Fedora European Team</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>CentOS + Fedora</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fedora European Contributors objectives, goals and more. This presentation will be more like a debate.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description></description>
      <persons>
          <person id="451">Chitlesh Goorah</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="46">
      <start>13:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>H.2214</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Organisation of Fedora French Users</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>CentOS + Fedora</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction to the local organisation of Fedora French Users&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The presentation will deal about how a local community is organising itself to promote Fedora locally. As soon as a new team has given itself the appropriate tools to promote Fedora on the web, it was ready to spread the right words about the principles that govern the Fedora Community.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="461">Thomas Canniot</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://fedoraproject.org/wiki/FUDCon/FUDConBrussels2007?action=AttachFile&amp;do=get&amp;target=intro-fedora.odp">Slides (OOo)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="48">
      <start>09:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>H.2214</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Java Status on Fedora</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>CentOS + Fedora</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Java Status on Fedora&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description></description>
      <persons>
          <person id="481">Tom Tromey</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="49">
      <start>15:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>H.2214</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Logical Volume Management</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>CentOS + Fedora</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Upcoming enhancements to LVM2 and device-mapper.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;LVM2 is the disk volume manager used by both Fedora and CentOS. This presentation will discuss ideas for enhancements to both kernel and userspace packages, including a summary of work already in progress as well as some &amp;#39;blue sky&amp;#39; thinking. Come along and share your ideas!&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="491">Alasdair Kergon</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="50">
      <start>11:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>H.2214</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Fedora&#39;s plans for 2007 + Q&amp;A</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>CentOS + Fedora</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fedora&amp;#39;s plans for 2007, the roadmap, the goals, and Q&amp;amp;A about any topic related to Fedora.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description></description>
      <persons>
          <person id="501">Max Spevack</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="51">
      <start>17:30</start>
      <duration>00:30</duration>
      <room>H.2214</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>SystemTap on Fedora</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>CentOS + Fedora</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://fedoraproject.org/wiki/SystemTap&#34;&gt;SystemTap&lt;/a&gt; is a tool for gathering and investigating system-wide information about a running Linux system.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SystemTap eliminates the tedious instrument, compile, reinstall, reboot sequence involved in data collection.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="511">Bryn Reeves</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="52">
      <start>15:00</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>Chavanne</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>GDB Tracepoints</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Development and Languages</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;GDB and tracepoint debugging&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tracepoint debugging allows a developer to observe a program as it runs with minimal impact on its real-time behavior.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jim&amp;#39;s work, building on the Linux kprobes facility and GDB&amp;#39;s existing tracepoint support, allows GDB to debug the Linux kernel it is running under, using source-level expressions and source code locations.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="521">Jim Blandy</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="../../slides/maintracks/gdb_tracepoints.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
          <link href="http://video.fosdem.org/2007/FOSDEM2007-GDBTracePoints.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="55">
      <start>16:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.124</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>The future of the Bugday project</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Gentoo</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The talk will be about how the Bugday project is evolving at the moment with all the new team members and new ideas.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It will be a completely non-technical talk.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description></description>
      <persons>
          <person id="551">Alexander Færøy</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="56">
      <start>14:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.124</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>What makes Gentoo a community based distribution?</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Gentoo</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What makes Gentoo a community based distribution ?&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description></description>
      <persons>
          <person id="561">Christel Dahlksjaer</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="57">
      <start>11:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.124</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Gentoo&#39;s inner working: The Council</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Gentoo</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;more details soon&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description></description>
      <persons>
          <person id="571">Mike Frysinger</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="60">
      <start>09:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.124</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Java on Gentoo</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Gentoo</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, Gentoo/Recruiting co-lead and Gentoo java developer Petteri Räty, provides an overview of Java support for Gentoo Linux.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Gentoo/Java project provides support for Java on everyone&amp;#39;s favorite Linux distro, Gentoo Linux.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The project provides a wide variety of Java runtimes and development kits, applications, libraries, and utilities. This talk will provide an overview of what you can expect from Gentoo as a Java user or developer.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Java team has for some years successfully used overlays as a way to involve users so this talk also provides ideas on how to get involved in Gentoo development using overlays.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="601">Joshua Nichols</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://dev.gentoo.org/~betelgeuse/GentooJavaFOSDEM07.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="61">
      <start>15:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.124</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Portage - A look under the surface</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Gentoo</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This talk will take a closer look at some of the new Portage features added in the Portage-2.1 series and how they can be used.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It will also discuss some commonly requested features and try to explain why they haven&amp;#39;t been implemented yet.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="611">Marius Mauch</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="62">
      <start>10:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.124</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Programing with Paludis</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Gentoo</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Programing with Paludis&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introductory talk in Paludis&amp;#39; paradigm and how to use its C++ and Ruby API.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="621">Danny van Dyk</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="64">
      <start>12:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.124</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Release Engineering: Tinderbox testing</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Gentoo</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Gentoo Release Engineering, Genkernel, and the Catalyst Release-building tool.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The talk will cover the Gentoo Release Engineering release cycle, Gentoo hosted projects catalyst and genkernel, and also the release Engineering automated build scripts/system that is used to locate problems before the release cycle begins.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="641">Chris Gianelloni</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="66">
      <start>13:15</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>H.1302</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Bling it up - make it sexy!</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>GNOME</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The talk &amp;#34;Bling it up - make it sexy!&amp;#34; will present certain ways how to achieve embellishment for your own application-development using cairo, librsvg and other usual suspects.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The presented techniques will be demonstrated with the help of a bling&amp;#39;ed up example program written in C. There will be gradients, rounded corners, blurs, fades, animation and so on... and sourcecode.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The intended audience is expected to already know a bit about cairo and gtk+. It will not be a talk for beginners.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="661">Mirco Müller</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="68">
      <start>16:15</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>H.1302</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Overview of the Gnome Developer Platform</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>GNOME</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The talk will introduce the Gnome Development Platform to new developers.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The talk will cover the components and technologies that are available, how they are related and how to get started using them.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The session will leave time for questions.&#xA;The goal is to use the feedback to improve the offered platform documentation.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="681">Marc-André Lureau</person>
          <person id="682">Stefan Kost</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="70">
      <start>14:00</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>H.1302</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Easy databases with Glom</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>GNOME</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Easy databases with Glom&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description></description>
      <persons>
          <person id="701">Murray Cumming</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="73">
      <start>09:00</start>
      <duration>00:15</duration>
      <room>H.1302</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>CrossDesktop</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the GNOME/KDE integration developer room.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sunday morning is shared with KDE for common topics and KDE/GNOME integration.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="731">Christophe Fergeau</person>
          <person id="732">Bart Coppens</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="77">
      <start>15:30</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>H.1302</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Why do we do it ?</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>GNOME</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Navigating the minefield: a personal guide to contributing to free software&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description></description>
      <persons>
          <person id="771">Dave Neary</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="79">
      <start>15:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.115</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>GNUstep Database Library 2</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>OpenGroupware + GNUstep</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[[http://www.gnustep.org/resources/documentation/Developer/GDL2/GDL2.html] GNUstep Database Library 2]&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description></description>
      <persons>
          <person id="791">Matt Rice</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="80">
      <start>11:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.115</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>GNUstep for Embedded Devices</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>OpenGroupware + GNUstep</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;GNUstep for Embedded Devices e.g. Zaurus or Mobile Phones&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The recent announcement of the Apple iPhone - which is reported to use Cocoa for the GUI - has again shown that Objective-C and the OpenSTEP system can really be used in embedded devices.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Topics to cover in this presentation:&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; why does one want to run GNUstep on embededed devices?&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; what is different on embedded devices?&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; what is needed to develop applications for embedded devices?&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; why is it currently run as a separate project (mySTEP)?&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; examples: Sharp Zaurus, Acer n30, Nokia N770, OpenMoko, ...&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="801">Nikolaus Schaller</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="81">
      <start>14:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.115</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Étoilé: a Desktop Environment</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>OpenGroupware + GNUstep</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.etoile-project.org/&#34;&gt;Étoilé&lt;/a&gt;: a Desktop Environment&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description></description>
      <persons>
          <person id="811">Quentin Mathé</person>
          <person id="812">Nicolas Roard</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="82">
      <start>10:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.115</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>FortyTwo Semistructured DB</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>OpenGroupware + GNUstep</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sourceforge.net/projects/fortytwo&#34;&gt;FortyTwo&lt;/a&gt; – Towards a Semistructured Database System&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Agenda:&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; About the Project&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; Motivation&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; Theoretical Background&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Architecture&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; Data- and Servicemodel&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; Architectural Overview of FortyTwo&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Positioning&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; Comparison with other semistructured database systems, with Coredata etc.&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Showtime&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; Demonstration&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; Current State&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt; Summary and future Directions&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="821">Oliver Langer</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="90">
      <start>15:00</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>Janson</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Secure Communications with Jabber</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Internet Services</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, Peter Saint-Andre will discuss the existing security features of Jabber technologies and how they are being extended to ensure complete privacy of communication over the Internet.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When you chat with a friend in your living room or a colleague in your office, you expect the conversation to be private. Unfortunately, your online conversations may not be private -- it all depends on what technology you use.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are many reasons why Jabber is more secure than existing IM and presence technologies, so Peter will explain those and how they help prevent spam on the Jabber network.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He will also talk about the Intermediate Certification Authority that Jabber recently launched to issue free digital certificates for Jabber servers.&#xA;Finally he will talk about the end-to-end encryption technology they are developing for complete privacy of instant messaging.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="901">Peter Saint-Andre</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="../../slides/maintracks/jabber.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
          <link href="http://video.fosdem.org/2007/FOSDEM2007-SecureCommunicationsWithJabber.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="93">
      <start>14:00</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>AW1.105</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Jaiku: Jabber the mobile</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Jabber</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How to map a desktop IM protocol for mobile use: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jaiku.com/&#34;&gt;Jaiku&lt;/a&gt; combines rich presence and group messaging on the web and on the mobile, powered by Jabber.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After an introduction into Jaiku, this presentation shows how Jaiku uses XMPP protocols and highlights the associated challenges, touching on network coverage, battery usage, sporadic attention, low input-rates.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The presentation closes with a small demo.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="931">Mika Raento</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="94">
      <start>12:30</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>AW1.105</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Give me a Jingle</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Jabber</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.xmpp.org/extensions/xep-0166.html&#34;&gt;Jingle XEPs&lt;/a&gt; add support to XMPP for session-based features such as voice, video and file transfer.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This talk will discuss the justification for these extensions, what they are trying to achieve, and how they work, taking a look at the current state of the standards and their implementations.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="941">Robert McQueen</person>
          <person id="942">Peter Saint-Andre</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="95">
      <start>13:15</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>AW1.105</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>OneTeam</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Jabber</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A Mozilla/XUL Jabber application.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.process-one.net/en/oneteam/&#34;&gt;OneTeam&lt;/a&gt; is a Mozilla based client, focusing on the enterprise market and introducing innovative productivity oriented features. It can be run from the web or as a standalone desktop client.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This talk will describe the design approach behind the new OneTeam client, the target features and the project roadmap. The talk will close with a&#xA;demonstration of OneTeam&amp;#39;s most current version. We will then provide accounts to visitors, to access the Web version after the talk.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="951">Mickaël Rémond</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="96">
      <start>16:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.105</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Follow-up Q&amp;A and Lightning Talks</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Jabber</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a follow-up to his talk in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://fosdem.org/2007/schedule/tracks/internetservices&#34;&gt;Internet Services track&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;http://fosdem.org/2007/schedule/events/jabber&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;Secure Communications with Jabber&amp;#39;&lt;/a&gt;, this Q&amp;amp;A session with &lt;a href=&#34;http://fosdem.org/2007/schedule/speakers/peter+saint-andre&#34;&gt;Peter Saint-Andre&lt;/a&gt; provides more time for answering questions.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Also, last-minute lightning talks (5 min. each) will be scheduled in at the end of this slot.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="961">Peter Saint-Andre</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="97">
      <start>10:00</start>
      <duration>02:30</duration>
      <room>AW1.105</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Jabber Sprint using Twisted</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Jabber</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This short software development spree (sprint) is intended for developers to get acquainted with developing special purpose Jabber clients and server-side components.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We will use &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twistedmatrix.com/&#34;&gt;Twisted&lt;/a&gt; to explain several protocol concepts in detail and show how to deal with asynchronous protocol handling.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twistedmatrix.com/&#34;&gt;Twisted&lt;/a&gt; is an event-driven networking framework written in Python. It excels in writing applications that use one or more networking protocols in an asynchronous fashion, without resorting to multi-threading. Twisted includes implementations of a large number of protocols, among which XMPP.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="971">Ralph Meijer</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="103">
      <start>14:00</start>
      <duration>03:00</duration>
      <room>H.2213</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Distro DevJam</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>GNU Classpath + OpenJDK DevJam</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The goal of this session is to improve the distro packaging guidelines (filesystem layout, packaging inter-dependencies, browser integration, jpackage.org integration, developer guidelines, etc.) used across GNU/Linux distributions for Java libraries and programs.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Success for the DevJam would be demonstrated by community agreement towards cross-distro Java policy augmented by distro specific developer guidelines for implementing the policy.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1031">Thomas Fitzsimmons</person>
          <person id="1032">Tom Marble</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://blogs.sun.com/tmarble/resource/FOSDEM-2007/FOSDEM-2007-RedHat.pdf">[PDF] Java and RedHat</link>
          <link href="http://blogs.sun.com/tmarble/resource/FOSDEM-2007/FOSDEM-2007-Debian-Ubuntu.pdf">[PDF] Java in Debian and Ubuntu</link>
          <link href="http://people.redhat.com/fitzsim/fosdem-2007/fosdem-2007.sxi">[OOo] Java and RedHat</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="105">
      <start>10:00</start>
      <duration>03:00</duration>
      <room>H.2213</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>OpenJDK</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>GNU Classpath + OpenJDK DevJam</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sun will discuss the roadmap for the OpenJDK project including goals and code release plans.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sun will ask the community to participate in a discussion of governance models and contribution policies as to facilitate platform innovation while respecting the Java Community Process (JCP). &#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Current operations plans for version control, bug tracking, patch submission and testing will also be covered.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Engineers from the compiler team, the HotSpot team, the Java2D team and the Quality team will also give technical lightning talks.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This will be an interactive session with plenty of opportunities to ask Sun questions about OpenJDK.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1051">Mark Reinhold</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://blogs.sun.com/mr/resource/openjdk-fosdem-2007.pdf">[PDF] Mark Reinhold: OpenJDK Overview</link>
          <link href="http://blogs.sun.com/tmarble/resource/FOSDEM-2007/FOSDEM-2007-Java2D.pdf">[PDF] Igor Nekrestyanov: Java2D</link>
          <link href="http://blogs.sun.com/tmarble/resource/FOSDEM-2007/FOSDEM-2007-HotSpot.pdf">[PDF] Peter Kessler: HotSpot</link>
          <link href="http://blogs.sun.com/tmarble/resource/FOSDEM-2007/FOSDEM-2007-compiler.pdf">[PDF] Peter von der Ahé: Java compiler</link>
          <link href="http://blogs.sun.com/tmarble/resource/FOSDEM-2007/FOSDEM-2007-Quality.pdf">[PDF] David Herron: Quality</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="106">
      <start>14:00</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>Janson</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>JBoss BPM</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Internet Services</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Open source moving up the stack to JBoss BPM: a deep look at BPM in the scope of JBoss jBPM, focusing on the benefits for the developers.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Open source moves up the stack. From OS, over application server and now to BPM.&#xA;BPM is typically associated with high level business analysis and not having to write code.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This session will give a different perspective. In fact, there are many process languages: some targeted for business analysts, some targeted at specific aspects of software development. An example of the latter could be the overview of asynchronous architectures.&#xA;The focus will be on the benefits for the developers. Also we include a good description of how BPM is more about improving communication between business analysts and developers, rather then trying to avoid coding.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1061">Tom Baeyens</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="../../slides/maintracks/jboss_bpm.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
          <link href="http://video.fosdem.org/2007/FOSDEM2007-JBoss.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="108">
      <start>16:30</start>
      <duration>00:30</duration>
      <room>H.1301</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>KDE e.V.</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>KDE</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;KDE e.V. - The organization behind the project&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A big Free Software project such as the KDE e.V. needs some administrative care. This talks outlines the why and the how of KDE e.V. the foundation that is the legal representative of the KDE project. The mission of KDE e.V. is to support the development in the project.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1081">Sebastian Kügler</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://www.kde.org/kdeslides/fosdem2007/2007-02-sebas-kde_ev.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="109">
      <start>09:00</start>
      <duration>03:00</duration>
      <room>H.1301</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Free Educational Software: working together</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>KDE</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With the emergence of educational Linux distributions, Free Educational Software begins to reach schools. This BoF aims to make all people involved&#xA;in Edutainment (packagers, developers, ...) meet together and present their work in order to start collaborating better.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description></description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1091">Anne-Marie Mahfouf</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="110">
      <start>15:00</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>H.1301</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>KDE 4</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>KDE</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;KDE4 - where are we and where are we going.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jos will outline what the current status of the KDE 4.0 development cycle is, and what the KDE project wants to archieve in the KDE 4 series.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some screenshots showing the current new stuff.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1101">Jos Poortvliet</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://www.kde.org/kdeslides/fosdem2007/2007-02-poortvliet-kde4.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="111">
      <start>14:00</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>H.1301</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Krita: Present and Future</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>KDE</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Krita is the painting and image editing suite for KOffice. The talk will focus on its recent developments and the future KDE4 version.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Krita has been innovating itself for a while now. Already available features interesting for image editing include the possibility of CMYK colors and&#xA;16 bit per channel, while other features like a basic watercolor simulation could interest artists.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The next version of Krita will be based on the new KDE4 and KOffice2 technologies. The long-awaited change towards KDE4 for development provided a great incentive&#xA;to reshape the whole of KOffice, and Krita will be using these new architectures to provide an even better integration with the rest of the KOffice suite. This&#xA;intermingling goes both ways: not only will Krita be able to have better support for embedding other applications, the whole of KOffice now shares libraries&#xA;that were already present in Krita 1.6.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This talk will consist of two parts. One part will be looking at the recent changes and features in the last KDE3 based 1.6 branch. The other part will try to give&#xA;an overview of the more interesting features that are scheduled for the next KDE4 based release, offering a view at what could be expected.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1111">Bart Coppens</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://www.kde.org/kdeslides/fosdem2007/2007-02-coppens-krita_present_and_future.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="114">
      <start>13:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>Ferrer</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>GPG/PGP Keysigning</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Key Signing</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;GPG/PGP Key Signing session.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;http://fosdem.org/2007/keysigning#gpg&#34;&gt;http://fosdem.org/2007/keysigning#gpg&lt;/a&gt; for details.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1141">Wouter Verhelst</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="120">
      <start>10:00</start>
      <duration>01:30</duration>
      <room>Lameere</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>LPI exam session 3</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>LPI Certification</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;LPI Exam session #3&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;http://fosdem.org/2007/lpi&#34;&gt;http://fosdem.org/2007/lpi&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1201">Klaus Behrla</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="121">
      <start>13:00</start>
      <duration>01:30</duration>
      <room>Lameere</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>LPI exam session 4</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>LPI Certification</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;LPI Exam Session #4&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;http://fosdem.org/2007/lpi&#34;&gt;http://fosdem.org/2007/lpi&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1211">Klaus Behrla</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="122">
      <start>15:00</start>
      <duration>01:30</duration>
      <room>Lameere</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>LPI exam session 5</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>LPI Certification</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;LPI Exam Session #5&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;http://fosdem.org/2007/lpi&#34;&gt;http://fosdem.org/2007/lpi&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1221">Klaus Behrla</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="123">
      <start>10:40</start>
      <duration>00:15</duration>
      <room>Ferrer</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Amarok</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Lightning Talks</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A lightning talk about Amarok, a jukebox audio player&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this talk the speaker will show advanced and hard to find features&#xA;of Amarok. &#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;About Amarok:&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Amarok is an audio player with jukebox capabilities and many useful,&#xA;partly well hidden features.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1231">Sven Krohlas</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="../../slides/lightningtalks/Amarok.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="124">
      <start>10:20</start>
      <duration>00:15</duration>
      <room>Ferrer</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Babel Free Auditing System</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Lightning Talks</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A lightning talk about Babel, a security auditing system.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The lightningtalk will be a graphical demonstration about how Babel works. &#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;About Babel Enterprise:&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Babel is an enterprise-grade auditing system to manage a consistency on security policy between different systems in a non-homogeneus architecture. Babel allows to manage very different operating systems, like AIX, Solaris, Windows 2000, Windows XP, Linux, *BSD or HPUX.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Babel allows administrator team to monitor the hardening level of their systems and keep constantly monitored, using periodic policy polling, and of course, a WEB Based, graphical reporting, and of course, a centralized management for all systems.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Babel uses a pragmatic point of view and try to evaluate security aspects on your systems that could be improved by the administrators. Babel is not intrusive, it only collect information and manage all this information.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Currently we are working with agents for Solaris, AIX, WindowsXP/2000/2003 and GNU/Linux versions (Debian, Ubuntu and SUSE).&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1241">Manuel Arostegui</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="../../slides/lightningtalks/Babel.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="125">
      <start>09:40</start>
      <duration>00:15</duration>
      <room>Ferrer</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Balloon Open Hardware License</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Lightning Talks</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A lightning talk about the Balloon Open Hardware License.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The talk will be primarily about the Balloon Open Hardware&#xA;Licence on which we are currently solicting feedback. It will explain&#xA;why the licence is different from software Licences, distinguishing&#xA;between designers, manufacturers, and users, who needs different&#xA;rights and protections. We are actively seeking feedback on this&#xA;Licence, in order to make it widely suitable. A short history of the&#xA;Balloon Project and current status will be included.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;About the Balloon Project:&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Balloonboard is primarily about the design and use of the&#xA;Balloon series of open hardware boards. First Balloon hardware was in&#xA;2002, and Balloon2 was used in products of a couple of companies, for&#xA;Disabled speech sythesisers and seismometers. Balloon3 is now out,&#xA;with built-in FPGA, being used in University teaching (robotics) via&#xA;the Cambridge/MIT MDP.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have created a new Open Hardware licence suitable for all such Open&#xA;Hardware, and are keen to see Balloon spread to other educational&#xA;institutions and products, and the licence be refined and used&#xA;elsewher.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1251">Wookey</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="../../slides/lightningtalks/Balloon.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="126">
      <start>14:00</start>
      <duration>00:15</duration>
      <room>Ferrer</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>CCAPI2</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Lightning Talks</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A lightning talk about CCAPI2, an algorithm trading platform.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The presentation will create in fifteen minutes a full trade system, that will be backtested against a prerecorded market situation. The outcome of this trading day is then presented and quickly discussed.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;About CCAPI2:&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The CCAPI2 is an algorithm trading plattform. With CCAPI2, users can create automated trade systems for trading stocks, futures, commodities and other financial instruments. The project contains forums, documentation, a mailing list and proper release cycles. At this time, seven more or less active developers take care of the 150 downloads per month.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1261">Ulrich Staudinger</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="../../slides/lightningtalks/CCAPI2.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="132">
      <start>11:00</start>
      <duration>00:15</duration>
      <room>Ferrer</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>LogiLogi Manta</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Lightning Talks</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A lightning talk about LogiLogi Manta, an incremental and entity-oriented discussion environment.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The speaker will talk about FOSS (especially web 2.0) for the humanities, &#xA;about the ideas behind LogiLogi Manta, like entity-oriented &#xA;philosophy and combining full openness with quality-control, and &#xA;last but not least about LogiLogi Manta itself.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;About LogiLogi Manta:&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;LogiLogi Manta targets on making incremental and entity- oriented &#xA;philosophical discussions possible. Core values are openness, &#xA;relativism and quality of content. Manta is bringing together the &#xA;idea of writeups of everything2.com and the transparency of Wiki&amp;#39;s &#xA;and the posibillity for rating content from multiple viewpoints, &#xA;hierarchical tagging, meaningfull urls, link-types, and more. &#xA;&lt;/p&gt;  &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Manta was started with a modest grant from the Philosophy &#xA;department of the (Dutch) Rijksuniversiteit Groningen.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1321">Wybo Wiersma</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="../../slides/lightningtalks/LogiLogiManta.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="133">
      <start>15:20</start>
      <duration>00:15</duration>
      <room>Ferrer</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Mapyrus</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Lightning Talks</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A lightning talk about Mapyrus, software for creating PostScript plots.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This talk is a quick introduction to Mapyrus, describing how it provides a&#xA;scripting/BASIC&#xA;type language for drawing shapes, labels and images to various graphics output&#xA;formats. The method of combining sequences of steps to create different types&#xA;of&#xA;output will be shown.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt; &#xA;&lt;p&gt;Several nice features of Mapyrus will be demonstrated, such as transparent&#xA;colours and use&#xA;of blending modes, user-defined TrueType and PostScript fonts, using&#xA;clipping polygons to avoid drawing inside/outside an area, protecting&#xA;areas of page to avoid over-lapping labels or symbols and a sinkhole&#xA;algorithm for finding position for labelling polygons.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Finally, some real world mapping and charting applications of Mapyrus will be&#xA;shown,&#xA;using data read from Geographic Information Systems (GIS) mapping datasets&#xA;and a relational database.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;About Mapyrus:&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mapyrus is Java software built on the Java2D library for creating plots of&#xA;points, lines, polygons and labels to&#xA;PostScript (high resolution, up to A0 paper size), Portable Document Format&#xA;(PDF), Scalable Vector Graphics (SVG) format and web image output formats.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mapyrus is released under the LGPL license.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1331">Simon Chenery</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="../../slides/lightningtalks/Mapyrus.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="134">
      <start>11:20</start>
      <duration>00:15</duration>
      <room>Ferrer</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>MetaLinks</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Lightning Talks</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A lightning talk about MetaLinks: XML mirror lists.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The lightning talk will cover a basic metalink, what problem metalinks&#xA;hope to solve and what support for them is already out there, showing&#xA;the difference between Metalinks and some other solutions currently&#xA;used. &#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;About MetaLinks:&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Metalinks tools project is there to create tools to handle and&#xA;generate Metalinks. Metalinks are XML mirror lists with verification&#xA;information (and more).&#xA;Currently the project has created a command line tool to generate&#xA;these files and the Metalink standard is already supported by mutliple&#xA;download managers (see http://metalinker.org/ for a full list).&#xA;Metalinker.org is where the XML format specs and general information&#xA;about Metalinks can be found (including news).&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1341">Bram Neijt</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="../../slides/lightningtalks/MetaLinks.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="136">
      <start>16:20</start>
      <duration>00:15</duration>
      <room>Ferrer</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Mozart-Oz</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Lightning Talks</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A lightning talk about Mozart-Oz: a multi-paradigm programming language.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This talk will introduce Mozart-Oz, a multi-paradigm programming language supporting functional, concurrent, object-oriented, logic and constraint programming paradigms, offering transparent support for distributed programming. Recently, the project has moved from a Consortium of Universities to a more open governance model in order to welcome new developers. This programming language is being used for development in some European projects and for teaching at universities in Belgium, Sweden, Poland, Colombia and USA, using the book &amp;#34;Concepts, Techniques, and Models of Computer Programming&amp;#34;. Unfortunately, it is not well known out of the academia and we would like to present it to the FOSDEM community.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1361">Boriss Mejias</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="../../slides/lightningtalks/MozartOz.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="139">
      <start>16:00</start>
      <duration>00:15</duration>
      <room>Ferrer</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>OpenEmbedded</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Lightning Talks</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A lightning talk about OpenEmbedded, and other build-systems.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;OpenEmbedded can be classified as build-system. It heavily&#xA;relies on build-systems of Free Software projects. Exactly this will&#xA;be the content of the lightning talk. We will take a look at badly&#xA;written buildsystems including fontconfig and glibc, understand why&#xA;these things are bad and how these issues can be resolved. At the end&#xA;we will look into some requirements you should take into account when&#xA;picking a buildsystem for your project. &#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;About OpenEmbedded:&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Deterministic and flexible system to build Embedded&#xA;Linux Distributions, Toolchains and Packages&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1391">Holger Freythe</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="../../slides/lightningtalks/OpenEmbedded.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="140">
      <start>15:00</start>
      <duration>00:15</duration>
      <room>Ferrer</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>OpenOffice.org port for Mac OS X</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Lightning Talks</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A lightning talk about the Mac OS X port of OpenOffice.org&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; what is Mac port inside the project&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; people: who / where&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; communication between developers, tools&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; how  works the project : schedule, QA, issues, development management&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; development problems : marry fully OpenSource project with non-open source platform is not so easy, find resources &#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;i&gt;About OpenOffice.org:&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;&#xA;OpenOffice.org project ( http://www.openoffice.org ) is a fully Open Source project, with a good portability on several platform / OS&#xA;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1401">Eric Bachard</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="../../slides/lightningtalks/MacOOosX.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="142">
      <start>14:40</start>
      <duration>00:15</duration>
      <room>Ferrer</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>OSSIE</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Lightning Talks</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A lightning talk about OSSIE, a Software Defined Radios(SDR) implementation.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The talk will introduce software defined&#xA;radio and talk about several open source SDR projects. The talk will focus on&#xA;explaining what SDR is, why the open source developer would be interested&#xA;in it, and ways to get started. &#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;About OSSIE:&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;OSSIE is an implementation of the Software Communication Architecture(SCA).&#xA;The SCA provides a structure for implementing Software Defined Radios&#xA;(SDR) using a component based architecture. OSSIE currently runs on&#xA;regular PC&amp;#39;s and a TI OMAP Starter Kit (OSK). OSSIE runs primarily on&#xA;Linux based machines (although other Unix&amp;#39;s should work OK).&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1421">Philip Balister</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="../../slides/lightningtalks/OSSIE.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="145">
      <start>10:00</start>
      <duration>00:15</duration>
      <room>Ferrer</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>phpAspect</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Lightning Talks</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A lightning talk about phpAspect, aspect-oriented programming in PHP.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The talk will be a quick overview of phpAspect and demonstrates&#xA;how this tool can be used to modularize web-specifics crosscutting&#xA;concerns like XSS faillures with a very simple use case. &#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;About phpAspect:&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In software engineering, the programming paradigm of aspect-oriented&#xA;programming (AOP), attempts to aid programmers in the separation of&#xA;technical concerns (persistence, logging, etc) from the business&#xA;logic.&#xA;This paradigm introduce a software entity, called aspect which, thanks&#xA;to a mechanism of weaving, can enrich portions of business logic with&#xA;technical processes.&#xA;In phpAspect this mechanism of weaving uses XSLT to perform source&#xA;code transformation.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1451">William Candillon</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="../../slides/lightningtalks/phpAspect.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="146">
      <start>15:40</start>
      <duration>00:15</duration>
      <room>Ferrer</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>PSPP</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Lightning Talks</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A lightning talk about PSPP: a Free replacement for SPSS.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The proprietary program called SPSS is widely used by the&#xA;&#x9;medics, psychologists and social scientists.  For many years&#xA;&#x9;there has been no Free program to replace it.  PSPP is an&#xA;&#x9;emulation of this proprietary program, designed to facilitate&#xA;&#x9;the transition to a Free desktop for traditonal SPSS users.&#xA;&#x9;I&amp;#39;ll be presenting what PSPP currently does now, what it may&#xA;&#x9;do in the future and how it could interact with other Free&#xA;&#x9;Software programs. &#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;About PSPP:&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#x9;PSPP is a program for statistical analysis of sampled data. It&#xA;&#x9;interprets commands in the SPSS language and produces tabular&#xA;&#x9;output in ASCII, PostScript, or HTML format.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#x9;PSPP development is ongoing. It already supports a large subset of&#xA;&#x9;SPSS&amp;#39;s transformation language. Its statistical procedure support is&#xA;&#x9;currently limited, but growing.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1461">John Darrington</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="../../slides/lightningtalks/PSPP.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="147">
      <start>11:40</start>
      <duration>00:15</duration>
      <room>Ferrer</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>ReaR</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Lightning Talks</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A lightning talk on Relax and Recover, a disaster recovery framework.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Short presentation on Rear (history, architecture, design, purpose).&#xA;A live demo (movie) of a real disaster recovery process will be shown&#xA;during the talk.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;About ReaR:&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Relax and Recover (abbreviated rear) is a highly modular disaster recovery&#xA;framework for GNU/Linux based systems, but can be easily extended to other&#xA;UNIX alike systems. The disaster recovery information (and maybe the&#xA;backups) can be stored via the network, local on hard disks or USB&#xA;devices, DVD/CD-R, tape, etc. The result is also a bootable image that is&#xA;capable of booting via PXE, DVD/CD and tape (OBDR).&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1471">Gratien D&#39;haese</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="../../slides/lightningtalks/ReaR.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="148">
      <start>14:20</start>
      <duration>00:15</duration>
      <room>Ferrer</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>SIP Communicator</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Lightning Talks</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A lightning talk about SIP Communicator, an audi/video softphone and IM client.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The talk would first go over major features of SIP Communicator and describe what sets it apart from a user point of view.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It would then describe aspects of the project that might be of interest to FOSS developers. One of the key characteristics of SIP Communicator is its flexibility and easy to use API. The client is built around an OSGi (www.osgi.org) core. All its functionalities are implemented as independent modules that also export services for use by plugin developers. This part of the talk would try to show how easy it is to use these services and create plugins for SIP Communicator or directly get involved and contribute to its development. &#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;About SIP Communicator:&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SIP Communicator is an open source (LGPL) audio/video Internet phone and instant messenger that supports    some of the most popular instant messaging and telephony protocols such as SIP, Jabber, AIM/ICQ, MSN and soon others like Yahoo and IRC.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1481">Emil Ivov</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="../../slides/lightningtalks/SIPcommunicator.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="150">
      <start>09:20</start>
      <duration>00:15</duration>
      <room>Ferrer</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Zzuf</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Lightning Talks</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A lightning talk about Zzuf, an input fuzzing bug hunter.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This talk will present zzuf&amp;#39;s internals and give a few examples&#xA;  of real life bugs in various widespread end-user applications that&#xA;  zzuf is able to find automatically.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;About Zzuf:&lt;/i&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;zzuf is a transparent application input fuzzer. Its purpose is&#xA;  to find bugs in applications by corrupting their user-contributed&#xA;  input. It works by intercepting file and network operations and&#xA;  changing random bits in the program&amp;#39;s input. zzuf&amp;#39;s behaviour is&#xA;  deterministic, making it easier to reproduce bugs.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1501">Sam Hocevar</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="../../slides/lightningtalks/Zzuf.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="151">
      <start>11:00</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>Janson</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Metasploit Framework</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Security</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.metasploit.com/&#34;&gt;Metasploit Framework&lt;/a&gt; is an open-source platform for developing and using exploit code.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This talk will cover the new features and development resources available in version 3.0 and some of the challenges faced by the project during the development process.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1511">H D Moore</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="../../slides/maintracks/metasploit.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
          <link href="http://video.fosdem.org/2007/FOSDEM2007-Metasploit.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="152">
      <start>14:00</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>Chavanne</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Turbocharging Linux with Mono</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Development and Languages</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this talk Miguel will discuss how they are using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mono-project.com/Main_Page&#34;&gt;Mono&lt;/a&gt; at Novell to increase the joy of programming and increase their productivity.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He will also discuss their efforts to assist Windows developers move their software to Linux, what they are providing to those developers today and what is in store for the future.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Miguel shall also showcase some major endorsements of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mono-project.com/Main_Page&#34;&gt;Mono&lt;/a&gt;.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1521">Miguel de Icaza</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://video.fosdem.org/2007/FOSDEM2007-TurboCachingLinuxWithMono.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="153">
      <start>12:00</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>Chavanne</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Mozilla</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Web</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(details will follow)&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description></description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1531">Mike Schroepfer</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://video.fosdem.org/2007/FOSDEM2007-Mozilla.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="157">
      <start>09:00</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>H.1309</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>AllPeers: Experiences with Mozilla and Future Plans</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Mozilla</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This talk will have two parts. In the first part, we discuss the benefits and challenges of building a complex application as a Firefox extension. In the second part, we discuss our future plans, with a specific focus on upcoming features of Mozilla that we are excited about and things that we would like to see added to Mozilla.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With AllPeers we have faced the unusual challenge of building a relatively large and complex application as a Firefox extension. This means that, unlike projects like Flock and Songbird, we have not been able to change the underlying Mozilla code base when it hasn&amp;#39;t fully met our requirements.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We discuss some of the specific issues we have faced (thread safety, RDF, encoding issues, integration with third-party libraries, etc.) and the solutions that we found. We also mention some of the main strengths of Firefox as a platform that have helped our project to be a success.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the second part of the talk, we go over some of our future plans. This includes adding true support for BitTorrent to Firefox in the short term, a strategy for efficient generation of HTML from a SQL datasource (&amp;#34;Mozilla Server Pages&amp;#34;) and our longer term plan to split AllPeers into two parts: a XULRunner-based engine and a much smaller Firefox extension that will serve as the user interface.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The latter will solve some of the issues we have experienced with hosting the entire application in Firefox and will open the way to layering alternative UIs (such as Internet Explorer) on top of our Mozilla-based engine.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1571">Matthew Gertner</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="158">
      <start>15:00</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>H.1309</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Mozilla Localization status report</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Mozilla</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mozilla Localization teams, a status report and whishlist.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Return of experience, wishes of the localisation teams (and specially the french one).&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tools proposition.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Outline :&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt; Introduction&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; How do we work in the frenchmozilla team&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; Wishes and improvement (from the french team and others)&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; Proposition of a tool&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; Conclusion&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; Discussion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1581">Philippe Dessante</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="159">
      <start>14:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>H.1309</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>L20n - A localization architecture proposal</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Mozilla</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Localizing software is still a challenge and a compromise between programming effort and localization quality. The talk will outline some unsolved issues so far and propose a new architecture to tackle those.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Localization of software brings up the same problems in every project, and not all of them have solutions so far. After analyzing the common requirements in the wild and within the Mozilla applications in particular, we found no existing architecture being able to bring the localization quality to software that users deserve.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;L20n is the code name for a proposed architecture that changes the way programs handle locale-dependent strings such that the quality of the localization is only limited by the amount of work a localizers spends, and not limited by architectural problems. We will show common localization pitfalls along with the proposed solutions.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;L20n is designed with Mozilla applications in mind, but should be interesting for other applications and frameworks, both for locally installed applications and web applications. We hope for participation from non-Mozilla hackers and localizers in particular at FOSDEM, and reserve a good deal of the allocated time for discussions.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1591">Axel Hecht</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="162">
      <start>10:30</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>H.1309</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>QA mozilla/xulrunner based applications</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Mozilla</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Challenges encountered doing QA on a xulrunner based application. QAing &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.joost.com/&#34;&gt;Joost (tm)&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description></description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1621">Ludovic Hirlimann</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="163">
      <start>15:45</start>
      <duration>02:15</duration>
      <room>H.1309</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Releasing Mozilla Localizations</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Mozilla</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mozilla will use the gathering of many of its European Localizers to discuss various aspects around releasing existing and new localizations of the Mozilla products.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We will have a series of discussions on various topics. The actual list of topics as well as the time spent on each will depend on what we actually need, but expect topics like Documentation, Build, Tools, Release process etc to be handled.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These won&amp;#39;t really be talks, and Axel will only moderate the discussions.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1631">Axel Hecht</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="165">
      <start>09:45</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>H.1309</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Extension Development with Thunderbird</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Mozilla</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An overview of how OpenPGP is integrated into Thunderbird, including the problems that the OpenPGP standards cause for mail clients.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://enigmail.mozdev.org/&#34;&gt;Enigmail&lt;/a&gt; is tightly integrated into Thunderbird. This is often not as straightforward as it may seem, since OpenPGP standards are incompatible to several email standards and implementation approaches used by Thunderbird. This talk gives an overview on these problems and how they are addressed.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1651">Patrick Brunschwig</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="167">
      <start>13:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.115</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Open Groupware: OGo/JOPE/SOPE</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>OpenGroupware + GNUstep</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Open Groupware: OGo / JOPE / SOPE&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description></description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1671">Marcus Müller</person>
          <person id="1672">Helge Hess</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="172">
      <start>12:00</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>H.1308</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>openSUSE Community</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>openSUSE</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A talk from an openSUSE Community member on Community history, ongoings, problems, challenges, and plans for the future.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;openSUSE, since SUSE Linux 10.0, is open up to the public with beta-testing; development and the release process is no longer all in-house. This talk will cover some thoughts on the response of such a change, other problems and challenges that the community is facing, as well as exciting projects made by the community.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1721">Francis Giannaros</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://files.opensuse.org/opensuse/en/6/64/Community.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
          <link href="http://ftp5.gwdg.de/pub/opensuse/FOSDEM/2007/fosdem2007-12_openSUSE_Community-1200.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
          <link href="http://ftp5.gwdg.de/pub/opensuse/FOSDEM/2007/fosdem2007-12_openSUSE_Community-320.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora/Low quality)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="173">
      <start>14:30</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>H.1308</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Usability research of KDE at openSUSE</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>openSUSE</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The KDE team at SUSE has been applying usability research principles to the user interfaces they design.&#xA;This talk presents their research methodology and the resulting applications.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Interfaces and Applications team at the SUSE research and development department in Nuremberg, Germany is composed of usability experts and KDE &#xA;developers. The team evaluated the start menus of common desktops including KDE 3.5, the GNOME main menu developed for SUSE Linux Enterprise 10 Desktop &#xA;and Windows Vista Beta 2.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Central to this research is a usability study where about 30 users of different types are divided up into four groups to perform a test cycle with &#xA;three phases:&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; Questionnaire: user&amp;#39;s habits during use of their commonly used start menu&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; Observation: execution of 13 different tasks stored on videotape for later evaluation&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; Questionnaire: user&amp;#39;s evaluation of the given start menu (joy of use, suitability to the task, controllability, etc.)&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;This aKademy talk will summarize the findings of these ongoing tests including showing video excerpts.&#xA;&#xA;The whole team then discussed the central functionality that an improved start menu for KDE 4 should have, and with the test results in mind, brain-stormed and produced mockups. For further discussion and testing a prototype, code-named &amp;#39;Kickoff&amp;#39;, was produced and iteratively refined.&#xA;&#xA;To validate this design, a fourth group of users repeated the usability tests with the prototype to get data for a comparison of old and new designs.&#xA;The talk will present major points of the discussion and results and of course will not miss to showcase the current &amp;#39;Kickoff&amp;#39; version.&#xA;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1731">Stephan Binner</person>
          <person id="1732">Will Stephenson</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://files.opensuse.org/opensuse/en/b/bb/FOSDEM2007-Usability_Research_for_KDE_at_openSUSE.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
          <link href="http://ftp5.gwdg.de/pub/opensuse/FOSDEM/2007/fosdem2007-15_Usability_research_of_KDE_at_openSUSE-1200.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
          <link href="http://ftp5.gwdg.de/pub/opensuse/FOSDEM/2007/fosdem2007-15_Usability_research_of_KDE_at_openSUSE-320.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora/Low quality)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="174">
      <start>12:45</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>H.1308</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Documentation: Lessons for Lizards</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>openSUSE</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A New Open Source Documentation Project: Lessons for Lizards&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lessons for Lizards (LfL) is a community cookbook-style book project for the openSUSE distribution licensed under the GFDL.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This talk will introduce the Lessons for Lizards project, show how to participate in this project, and present the tools available.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lessons for Lizards will ship with upcoming openSUSE releases on an equal footing with internally produced documentation. It covers more specific or exotic topics than the internally produced manuals (such as experimental software or complex setups).&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One aim of the LfL project is to enable the openSUSE community to actively participate in the openSUSE documentation. The other aim is to provide a cookbook for beginners and experts with step-by-step recipes and hands-on guides for topics not covered in the present documentation.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The book should be easy to write. To make this possible, SUSE provides a technical environment (SVN server, wiki), software (tools and scripts) and support (documentation, mailinglist).&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1741">Frank Sundermeyer</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://files.opensuse.org/opensuse/en/4/41/LfL_FOSDEM2007_presentation.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
          <link href="http://ftp5.gwdg.de/pub/opensuse/FOSDEM/2007/fosdem2007-13_Documentation_Lessons_for_Lizards-1200.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
          <link href="http://ftp5.gwdg.de/pub/opensuse/FOSDEM/2007/fosdem2007-13_Documentation_Lessons_for_Lizards-320.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora/Low quality)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="175">
      <start>15:30</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>H.1308</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Mono Workshop</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>openSUSE</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Mono workshop gives more details on how to work with mono.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Mono workshop gives more details on how to work with mono. The workshop after Miguels Mono talk, so you have the chance to get more information&#xA;here.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1751">Miguel de Icaza</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://ftp5.gwdg.de/pub/opensuse/FOSDEM/2007/fosdem2007-16_Mono_Workshop-1200.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
          <link href="http://ftp5.gwdg.de/pub/opensuse/FOSDEM/2007/fosdem2007-16_Mono_Workshop-320.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora/Low quality)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="176">
      <start>13:30</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>H.1308</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>OpenOffice - OpenXML</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>openSUSE</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A talk about the OpenXML integration in OpenOffice&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description></description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1761">Michael Meeks</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://ftp5.gwdg.de/pub/opensuse/FOSDEM/2007/fosdem2007-14_OpenOffice_OpenXML-1200.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
          <link href="http://ftp5.gwdg.de/pub/opensuse/FOSDEM/2007/fosdem2007-14_OpenOffice_OpenXML-320.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora/Low quality)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="177">
      <start>10:30</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>H.1308</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>OpenSync</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>openSUSE</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;OpenSync - Synchronization Framework for mobile devices.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A short introduction of OpenSync, a Synchronization Framework. The Framework is intended to synchronize all kind of mobile devices, applications and &#xA;services. The talk includes some details about the features of the upcoming OpenSync 0.30 version.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opensync.org/&#34;&gt;OpenSync&lt;/a&gt; is a Synchronization Framework. The framework is a desktop independent synchronization solution for all kind of mobile device and application. The plugin based architecture allows to enhance the support of new devices/protocols with providing a simple plugin. &#xA;There are so far OpenSync frontends for the command line, KDE and GNOME. At the moment framework supports: SyncML, IrMC and many other protocols and the KDE PIM and Evolution environment.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1771">Daniel Gollub</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://files.opensuse.org/opensuse/en/b/bb/OpenSync_FOSDEM_2007.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
          <link href="http://ftp5.gwdg.de/pub/opensuse/FOSDEM/2007/fosdem2007-10_OpenSync-1200.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
          <link href="http://ftp5.gwdg.de/pub/opensuse/FOSDEM/2007/fosdem2007-10_OpenSync-320.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora/Low quality)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="181">
      <start>10:00</start>
      <duration>00:30</duration>
      <room>H.1308</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Suspend to disk and to RAM</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>openSUSE</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Suspend to disk and to RAM, reports about the current state and workshop&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Suspend to disk and to RAM, reports about the current state.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After the Talk there will be a workshop, if you have problems with suspend this is the chance to work on it with the speakers and get your Laptop working with suspend.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1811">Pavel Machek</person>
          <person id="1812">Stefan Seyfried</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://atrey.karlin.mff.cuni.cz/~pavel/swsusp/swsusp2007.odp">Slides (OOo)</link>
          <link href="http://ftp5.gwdg.de/pub/opensuse/FOSDEM/2007/fosdem2007-09_Suspend_to_disk_and_to_RAM-1200.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
          <link href="http://ftp5.gwdg.de/pub/opensuse/FOSDEM/2007/fosdem2007-09_Suspend_to_disk_and_to_RAM-320.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora/Low quality)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="183">
      <start>11:15</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>H.1308</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>ThinkFinger</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>openSUSE</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ThinkFinger - Don&amp;#39;t bother if you lose your password, but please keep your finger safe.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction on ThinkFinger, a driver for the UPEK/STM fingerprint reader. The device is being found either as a standalone USB device, built into USB keyboards or built into laptops (Dell, IBM/Lenovo, Toshiba).&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ThinkFinger is a driver for the UPEK/SGS Thomson Microelectronics fingerprint reader (USB ID 0483:2016).&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The device is being found either as a standalone USB device, built into USB keyboards or built into laptops.&#xA;The following laptop vendors are using the device:&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; Dell&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; IBM/Lenovo&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; Toshiba&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;Toshiba is shipping their laptops either with the UPEK/SGS Thomson Microelectronics fingerprint reader or with a fingerprint reader built by AuthenTec. The AuthenTec fingerprint reader is *not* supported by ThinkFinger.&#xA;SONY laptops with the UPEK/SGS Thomson Microelectronics fingerprint reader are not supported.&#xA;&#xA;ThinkFinger is devided into two parts: libthinkfinger and pam_thinkfinger. libthinkfinger is a library to be used in order to communicate with the fingerprint reader.&#xA;&#xA;The talk will give insights about the low-level engineering (usbmon), the library as well as the PAM module.&#xA;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1831">Pavel Machek</person>
          <person id="1832">Timo Hoenig</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://files.opensuse.org/opensuse/en/c/cd/ThinkFinger-Talk-FOSDEM_2007.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
          <link href="http://atrey.karlin.mff.cuni.cz/~pavel/swsusp/thinkfinger.odp">Slides (OOo)</link>
          <link href="http://ftp5.gwdg.de/pub/opensuse/FOSDEM/2007/fosdem2007-11_ThinkFinger-1200.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
          <link href="http://ftp5.gwdg.de/pub/opensuse/FOSDEM/2007/fosdem2007-11_ThinkFinger-320.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora/Low quality)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="184">
      <start>16:30</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>H.1308</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Common package and patch management for SUSE Linux</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>openSUSE</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Zypp - SUSE package management&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Zypp is the integration of SUSE&amp;#39;s yast2 Package manager and Ximian&amp;#39;s libredcarpet. At Novell we used two solutions so far - Red Carpet and YaST &#xA;package manager - and decided to merge both in a best of breed approach. Zypp features brings SUSE package management technology to a world of new &#xA;possibilities like runtime dependencies on hardware, patterns, full-featured patches and Zenworks integration for a easy enterprise upgrade path.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this talk this technologies will be presented among the current integration of them into the products, the problems faced during the transition and the current roadmap for the future releases.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1841">Duncan Mac-Vicar Prett</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://files.opensuse.org/opensuse/en/b/bf/Zypp-fosdem-opensuse.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
          <link href="http://ftp5.gwdg.de/pub/opensuse/FOSDEM/2007/fosdem2007-17_Common_package_and_patch_management_for_SUSE_Linux-1200.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
          <link href="http://ftp5.gwdg.de/pub/opensuse/FOSDEM/2007/fosdem2007-17_Common_package_and_patch_management_for_SUSE_Linux-320.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora/Low quality)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="185">
      <start>10:00</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>Chavanne</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Plone 3.0</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Web</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Developer Preview of Plone 3.0&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.plone.org/&#34;&gt;Plone&lt;/a&gt; has become a popular choice for managing content with security, workflow, translations, and other services.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this talk we preview the important changes planned in Plone 3.0 for developing add-ons and customized sites with Plone.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1851">Paul Everitt</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://video.fosdem.org/2007/FOSDEM2007-Plone.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="186">
      <start>16:00</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>Chavanne</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Profiling Desktop Applications</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Development and Languages</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this talk Federico will examine the basics of how to do a performance investigation, of which profiling is just one part.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Performance has to be focused on tangible benefits: will users stop noticing an annoying delay ? Will making an operation faster make the program more usable ? Will I get more transactions per second, and do I really need them ?&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Doing an analysis of performance makes you feel good for various reasons: you end up using the scientific method, you get to really understand the code you are fixing, and you learn many obscure techniques along the way.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After this talk you will know how to do a performance investigation, and you will know about the basic tools you can use to profile your programs.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1861">Federico Mena Quintero</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://video.fosdem.org/2007/FOSDEM2007-ProfilingDesktopApplication.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="189">
      <start>12:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.117</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Elisa</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Python</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fluendo.com/elisa/&#34;&gt;Elisa&lt;/a&gt; is a project to create an open source cross platform media center solution.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While our primary development and deployment platform is GNU/Linux and Unix operating systems we also currently support Microsoft Windows and also hope to support MacOSX in the future.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Elisa runs on top of the GStreamer multimedia framework. In addition to personal video recorder functionality (PVR) and Music Jukebox support, Elisa will also interoperate with devices following the DLNA standard like Intel&amp;#39;s ViiV systems.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The talk is about Elisa&amp;#39;s history, its current features, how it interoperates with devices and other applications. Philippe will also explain the plans for Elisa as well as a little demo.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1891">Philippe Normand</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="190">
      <start>11:30</start>
      <duration>00:30</duration>
      <room>AW1.117</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Extending Python</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Python</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Learn why and how to extend Python using ctypes and Pyrex.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Python comes with batteries included, but sometimes you need more. And even more often you need faster batteries that reuse C/C++ libraries.&#xA;Pyrex, the pseudo language, and ctypes helps you in order to bind C libraries to Python modules. Includes real pieces of code.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1901">Bader Ladjemi</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="191">
      <start>15:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.117</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>ModularBot</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Python</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://savannah.nongnu.org/projects/modularbot/&#34;&gt;ModularBot&lt;/a&gt;, a modular IRC bot written using Python.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pierre will show how to write something modular, since it&amp;#39;s easy and often interesting to do. He will also try to show some funny things about the Python introspection features...&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1911">Pierre Ducroquet</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="192">
      <start>10:00</start>
      <duration>00:30</duration>
      <room>AW1.117</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Quality in Python</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Python</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;«Bind two birds together: they have twice as many wings. However they are unable to fly.» Best practices in Python explained.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Quality often come too late in a project life cycle. Python&amp;#39;s rigour helps making a project more maintainable but it isn&amp;#39;t enough. Better practices can help you being more effective. Code styles, testing, documentation, project packaging best practices explained.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1921">Bader Ladjemi</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="193">
      <start>14:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.117</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>SQLAlchemy and Elixir</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Python</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A short presentation of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sqlalchemy.org/&#34;&gt;SQLAlchemy&lt;/a&gt; (the Python SQL toolkit and Object Relational Mapper) and Elixir, which is a brand-new declarative layer on top of SQLAlchemy, with a syntax similar to that of Ruby on Rails&amp;#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.rubyonrails.org/rails/pages/ActiveRecord&#34;&gt;ActiveRecord&lt;/a&gt;.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sqlalchemy.org/&#34;&gt;SQLAlchemy&lt;/a&gt; acts as the glue between your python projects and your SQL database in a very elegant way. It is a very powerful tool but setting up everything can be a bit tedious, so we wrote Elixir, as a thin wrapper around SQLAlchemy to provide the ability to define model objects in a simpler (and quicker) way when you do not need the full expressiveness of SQLAlchemy&amp;#39;s manual mapper definitions.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1931">Gaëtan de Menten</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="196">
      <start>16:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.117</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>XML processing with ElementTree and lxml</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Python</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Python 2.5 now includes the &lt;a href=&#34;http://effbot.org/zone/element-index.htm&#34;&gt;ElementTree XML processing module&lt;/a&gt; to process XML documents and streams in an efficient, straightforward, pythonic way. This talk introduces the API on common use cases.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We also introduce a second implementation of the same API: &lt;a href=&#34;http://codespeak.net/lxml/&#34;&gt;lxml&lt;/a&gt;. This library based on libxml2/libxslt add further implement standard XPATH queries, XSTL processing and validation against schemas (XML Schema and RelaxNG).&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We will finally demonstrate sample usage of those libraries to process ODF and SVG documents.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1961">Olivier Grisel</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="197">
      <start>10:30</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.117</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>The Zope3 component architecture</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Python</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The aim of this talk is to show the use of the zope.interface module to formalize duck typing in python projects.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By contractualizing APIs, a python project can gain much modularity and then make it natural to plug objects together in a reusable thanks to the delegation pattern implemented by the zope.component sister module.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="1971">Olivier Grisel</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="200">
      <start>09:00</start>
      <duration>02:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.120</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Research and Libre Software (II)</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Research Room</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Presentation of reviewed short papers.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; Snapshot on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edos-project.org/&#34;&gt;EDOS&lt;/a&gt; distribution system: Radu Pop&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; New generation of Linux Meta-installers: Paulo Trezentos&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; Determining developer habits and intuition through the use of interactive chat sessions: Martin F Krafft&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; Identifying challenges for a productive and sustainable Open Source ecosystem: Jens Hardings&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="2001">Jens Hardings</person>
          <person id="2002">Paulo Trezentos</person>
          <person id="2003">Radu Pop</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://gsyc.escet.urjc.es/~herraiz/fosdem2007/papers/workshop-proposal.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
          <link href="http://gsyc.escet.urjc.es/~herraiz/fosdem2007/slides/edosDistribution-FOSDEM2007.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
          <link href="http://gsyc.escet.urjc.es/~herraiz/fosdem2007/papers/edosDistribution.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
          <link href="http://gsyc.escet.urjc.es/~herraiz/fosdem2007/slides/FOSDEM2006_v3.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
          <link href="http://gsyc.escet.urjc.es/~herraiz/fosdem2007/papers/NewGenMI_tools.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="202">
      <start>11:00</start>
      <duration>02:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.120</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Panels and open discussion</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Research Room</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Panel: Issues of Company Involvement in Open Source Software Projects&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; Motivation and presentation: Matthias Stuermer (chair)&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; Firms&amp;#39; involvement in the projects of the OS community (short presentation): Cristina Rossi&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; Open discussion&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt; Research and libre software:&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt; - what can research about libre software contribute to libre software development;&#xA; - what do developers feel about research&#xA; - some academics and developers (3 min. position talk each, then open discussion)&#xA;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="2021">Cristina Rossi</person>
          <person id="2022">Matthias Stuermer</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://gsyc.escet.urjc.es/~herraiz/fosdem2007/papers/stuermer_proposal.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
          <link href="http://gsyc.escet.urjc.es/~herraiz/fosdem2007/slides/ethz_Presentation_2007-02-25_IssuesOnCompanyInvolvementInOSS.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
          <link href="http://gsyc.escet.urjc.es/~herraiz/fosdem2007/papers/paper_brussels_20070219.pdf">Slides (PDF)</link>
          <link href="http://libresoft.urjc.es/videos/FOSDEM07/20070225_panel.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
          <link href="http://libresoft.urjc.es/videos/FOSDEM07/20070225_panel_Heymans.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
          <link href="http://libresoft.urjc.es/videos/FOSDEM07/20070225_Maemo-panel_Stuermer.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="204">
      <start>16:00</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>Janson</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Samba</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Internet Services</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Current State of Samba&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Samba has been around a long time, and just keeps trucking along, right ? Not quite...&#xA;Attend this talk to hear about what&amp;#39;s new in Samba, what the Samba3/Samba4 code is all about, why we aren&amp;#39;t an Active Directory Domain Controller yet (and why it&amp;#39;s hard) and why the CIFS protocol is likely to loom large in *your* future, even if you use nothing but Linux...&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="2041">Jeremy Allison</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://video.fosdem.org/2007/FOSDEM2007-Samba.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="205">
      <start>10:00</start>
      <duration>00:45</duration>
      <room>Janson</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Security Testing</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>Security</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Security testing not by the book&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A cheat sheet to efficient and accurate security testing and analysis, this overview is about what many penetration testers and ethical hackers just don&amp;#39;t get. The real world doesn&amp;#39;t conform 100% to rules but it is rules that get put into tools and courses which guide and often think for today&amp;#39;s security professionals. In this talk, we will examine various real-world networks, services, and applications and explain where the tester went wrong in the test and analysis.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Security testing is the means to measure and verify operational security and controls are working. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.osstmm.org/&#34;&gt;Open Source Security Testing Methodology Manual (OSSTMM)&lt;/a&gt; is an open, peer-reviewed specification for an accurate and thorough security test. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.osstmm.org/&#34;&gt;OSSTMM&lt;/a&gt; has been written for real-world security testing and metrics and a review of the last 4 years of OSSTMM research is used to create this interactive talk.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="2051">Pete Herzog</person>
      </persons>
      <links>
          <link href="http://video.fosdem.org/2007/FOSDEM2007-SecurityTesting.ogg">Video (Ogg/Theora)</link>
      </links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="214">
      <start>11:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.121</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Nouveau: What&#39;s new ?</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>X.org</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction of Nouveau, a new 3D-capable opensource display driver for nVidia GPUs.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will first introduce the nouveau project quickly.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project aims at improving the quality of open source drivers for nvidia cards. Targetted features include 3D, dual head support, better 2D/Xv support, deobfuscating the code, and much more.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I will introduce the project, talk about past and current developments, and try to peek at my crystal ball for future works.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="2141">Stéphane Marchesin</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="215">
      <start>13:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.121</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Second Life</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>X.org</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://secondlife.com/&#34;&gt;Second Life&lt;/a&gt; opens the source code: what happens when a company frees their software BEFORE they jump the shark&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Aaron Brashears from &lt;a href=&#34;http://lindenlab.com/&#34;&gt;Linden Lab&lt;/a&gt; discusses what happens when a company with a proprietary code base decides to open it up, and talk about some of the contributions that have already come in and some of the things that have the community buzzing (such as the community effort to design a plugin architecture).&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There will be a discussion of the architectural elements of the Second Life viewer, some of the ideas Linden Lab has for the future of the project, and what new technology is coming down the pipe for release.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="2151">Aaron Brashears</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="216">
      <start>10:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.121</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>X security framework</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>X.org</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A framework to add security policies which meet the needs of specific environments and use cases in place.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The original design of the X Window system treated all application as &amp;#39;friends&amp;#39;. Applications (i.e.) X clients had access to data, state information and resources of each other. Many use cases don&amp;#39;t allow such a policy.&#xA;In environments where the protection of confidentiality matters this behavior is undesirable.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first attempt to overcome this was the X-Security extension. It presented a fixed and rather simplistic security policy. It had proven itself to be unflexible and not useful.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here we present a framework to add security policies which meet the needs of the specific environment and use case in place.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="2161">Egbert Eich</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="217">
      <start>14:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.121</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>X.org Video Driver API Update</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>X.org</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unification of X.org video driver APIs&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The X.org video driver API has not supported the full range of hardware capabilities for several years.&#xA;The resulting driver-specific mechanisms have made general configuration systems hard and provided diverse capabilities not based on hardware abilities, but rather on the vageries of the development process. Unifying these interfaces and exposing common configuration mechanisms serves to both homogenize the X server functionality across all hardware platforms as well as provide an interface for new RandR functionality.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="2171">Keith Packard</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>  <event id="218">
      <start>15:00</start>
      <duration>01:00</duration>
      <room>AW1.121</room>
      <slug></slug>
      <title>Video on Dope</title>
      <subtitle></subtitle>
      <track>X.org</track>
      <type></type>
      <language></language>
      <abstract>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Video on Dope - Different Techniques to Accelerate XVideo Display with OpenGL&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </abstract>
      <description>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/X_video_extension&#34;&gt;XVideo&lt;/a&gt; with color keying has been notoriously problematic in the past (multiple heads, size restrictions, etc.), and it doesn&amp;#39;t work well with composited desktops.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For OpenGL-based compositing window managers like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.go-compiz.org/&#34;&gt;compiz&lt;/a&gt; and for OpenGL-based Xservers like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.freedesktop.org/wiki/Software_2fXgl&#34;&gt;Xgl&lt;/a&gt; the most straight-forward solution is to use OpenGL for doing the color conversion and scaling on-the-fly. On the other hand, OpenGL is so flexible that there is more than a single way to implement this - and all techniques have their advantages and drawbacks.&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA; </description>
      <persons>
          <person id="2181">Matthias Hopf</person>
      </persons>
      <links></links>
      <video></video>
      <end></end>
  </event>
  </day>
</schedule>
